you're yeah dude you're a little off
with that one can you redo that sentence
we'll be talking about his band crown
but I want to I want to emphasize my
exploration all these different
musicians that I'm having on my podcast
my childhood growing up I was always a
headphones kid I was always like
escaping into these different realms of
music I think that a lot of musicians
and DJs and stuff can probably relate
yeah now same thing for me I was always
I was the weird kid that was always
listening to music and yeah that's why I
fell in love with it was my escape it
was my own little reality away from the
one I didn't like absolutely I think
that I think that you know something
that's important in this podcast is to
express those dorky things that we kind
of brush over and really like emphasize
the importance of them because a lot of
so what would you what would you John
Rifai your guys's music oh man uh we say
we're like we're metalcore band okay yes
like metalcore I guess is like the
modern it's modern metal for like I
guess Millennials it's it's a relatively
kind of new thing my probably like the
like late like 2007 2010 I think is what
metal Corp it's like became like a John
er because before that they were calling
it like new metal and then like it kind
of evolved past that like I would say it
started with like he'll switch engage
and like Avenged Sevenfold
as crazy men today like my two favorite
when I was a kid walking in my
headphones yeah yeah trying to not get
beat up by rednecks who are driving by
and I'm sure in sevenfold dude yeah yeah
yeah so that's kind of like what started
metalcore and then like it kind of
evolved and turned into the thing like I
mean the stuff were like you know people
really when you when I was like listen
to this [__] so if you know the stuff
where people really like to you know
call you a [__] for wearing skinny
jeans and [__] like that like bands like
asking alexandria attack attack we Came
As Romans like they started doing all
that [__] and now like it's evolved in
psyche this
whole new thing there's bands like
knocked loose who's like a hardcore band
but they're metalcore yeah they're like
it's it's weird you'd like but yeah
we're a metalcore van and it's like such
a deep I can give like a [__]
probably to our [__] seminar on just
what metalcore is and how its evolved
but like you said metalcore is like I
think he said metal for Millennials like
you can't go back and be like you know
like you can't go back to like the 90s
and eighties and be like metalcore cuz
it wasn't around then and it's not like
Pantera or Metallica like every time
we're at the [__] gas station Jesus
like people are like y'all in a band
we're like yeah like we're what kind of
music metal like oh swag Metallica sure
yeah like I'm not gonna be able to
explain this to you yeah yeah yeah
exactly or we get disturbed they're like
yeah all heavy [__] I love disturbed and
it's like well it's weird with those
conversations is there like hey I'm
gonna asking question about about you so
I could tell you about myself yeah it's
like weird like I do when you ask about
someone when you're like hey you guys
are in a band oh that's good tell me
about your band like don't be like hey
are you like this because I know this
about this yeah and usually when those
conversations happen to us it's like
3:00 a.m. at a gas station show we just
had a show we're tired as [__] and like
me I'm a pretty I'm not overly nice like
you know you're a very nice guy I'm
probably not as nice as you so when like
I'm not feeling it and I don't want to
talk I'll just be like you have what the
[__] ever and I'll just kind of like say
[__] to get by and just be like all
right bye give me my [__] gas and my
energy drink you know I'm I'm pretty
like standoffish and cold when I want to
be but so yeah I usually just like yeah
yeah okay bye okay buddy yeah all right
see ya thanks Dan I mean I have those
times too where sometimes I just need to
like get away but I do that quite a bit
yeah I mean hey Turin and [__] as much
as you guys do and staying up late I
mean I know how that goes so with York
I'm going down this chair man I got to
get it fixed every time that I lean in
this specific right spot I just do it
all my all my work shirts do that to it
so you can't escape it I need to get
like a chair sponsorship for the podcast
that's why I'm scared to buy like a $300
chair cuz what if it just does that [__]
cuz all the chairs I've had does that
it's like I'm not spending $300 on a
[__] chair for it some more dogs on a
chair and that
you know shopping for anything nowadays
are just madness shopping for a chair
what could you search my chair and there
is 17,000 results yeah it's so stressful
and you have to you don't even like if
you're doing it online you don't even
get to sit in it but then but then if
you would go to Office Depot or
something and you're gonna be paying way
more for it or if you go to one of those
places where they have a Salesman still
like it's just weird like a people still
go to those places they have those but
if you're saying like I guess I was the
big lots we can go to Big Lots you know
they have a big lots next to everyone in
town you have one in town in Kelso it's
like next to jo-ann's fabrics
ok I've something but I never I do not
never know what the [__] Big Lots is so
I'm like I'm not going I think that it's
just stuff that like we had some extras
in the truck crashed and so we have to
sell them for cheap and so they send
them to Big Lots well you're the [__]
store yeah I don't know I don't know
Longview though Yeah right
but anyway so they have they have these
like salesman I don't even know Matt
know me I'm talking about my ass but and
they have these salesmen where you go
and it just be awkward for like trying
to buy a chair and someone's like trying
to tell you about the chair smack the
chair this can fit it [__] try to
really sell you on it look how [__]
nice this glides up and down you could
see one one big thing about about you
guys is music so I started to this
morning how's it go you know I want to
uptick on dead ground I want to look
like I look up some lyrics a little bit
I started looking up lyrics and I was
like okay and it's it's I was gonna like
bring up some specific lyrics I'm like
that's just corny at this point because
there was so many yeah I think I just
want to back up from specific lyrics
yeah yeah talk about the lyric writing
process because because for me like you
know being this this punk rock kid like
listening to this intense music a lot of
people will think like you're just you
know a lot of people see that on the
outside and you're just trying to be
destructive you're just loud but a lot
of times it's like processing these
things and a lot of the lyrics of these
music like Killswitch Engage avenge
those like some of my tops dude yeah and
those bands are David like if you
actually sit down listen that lyrics and
stuff
it's very intellectual like deep [__]
you gotta rewind it sometimes yeah yeah
and if you actually look in the meetings
and look into like what they're actually
saying it's like wow this is some really
like heartfelt thought-out [__] which is
another reason why I liked metal I liked
that there was purpose behind every word
that was being saying for the most part
you know yeah yeah it's very punchy like
every line can stand on its own yeah
yeah yeah and it was thought out and it
was you know it was heartfelt it was it
carried like actual human emotion and
you know not to dog rap because I
[__] love rap and [__] too but a lot
of that was you know at the time like
you know doing pills scissor [__]
[__] is the same lis money you know
yeah yeah yeah oh just mixed around yeah
also if you want to get just if you want
to have a rap battle at the end of this
weekend dude I can't rap at all or [__]
you'd be my ass dude I have to write all
right maybe later let's talk about lyric
reading yeah yeah who does lyrics for
dead guy
that's all be yeah okay so the process
for me so it like I'm definitely not the
smartest guy especially growing up like
I was I I was in the special classes for
like reading and writing so I'm not I'm
by no means like a pretty intelligent
guy I'm probably less intelligent than
most people but because of that I've
always tried and if you like look at
deck around our lyrics and stuff I
always try to be just cut and dry to the
point you don't have to think hard to
get the [__] message you know I
always try to just and I do that like
not just for myself because a listener
that's always what I liked and that's
why I want to do to people who listen to
our music you know I don't want to use
such big words we're like what the [__]
does that mean
I want like I say it you get it you got
to condense this insane emotion down
yeah yeah it's just like and like I'm
not gonna be I'm not gonna I'm not the
smartest guy in the room I'm not gonna
try to be here's what I'm trying to
[__] say I'm just gonna [__] say
and you know just like no wall between
listener and what I'm trying to convey
you know so my writing process excuse me
um especially for this last album we
just did it was mainly a lot of I would
just like we would we would demo out the
song and then I'd usually to be honest
just go to my [__] local bar by my
house
order a double tall vodka soda with lime
have probably like two or three of those
get [__] smashed not smash but like
by the by the time my session was done I
was definitely walking home you know oh
yeah yeah and just [__] sit there
with my headphones at the bar get drunk
and you know usually when I when I get
when I'm in that space it's I'm digging
kind of deep going back to things and
and you know alcohol is a pretty good
[__] like emotional lubricant for
stuff like that like when you're trying
to resurface like [__] from like your
past especially like with this album
that we just did I talk about a lot of
stuff from like my childhood and like
growing up and stuff like that so I
would just [__] have some drinks and
just say whatever the [__] was on my
mind at the time and that's and it's per
song thing so I just sat down was like
well what am I feeling what do I want to
[__] say in the song and I'll just go
and say it and that's that's how I was
in depth the process is it's that simple
you know it's so beautiful though I mean
it's such an art do you ever find it's
kind of like you know an analogy I was I
was visualizing you know like you're
you're searching for oil like you're
sitting there at the bar and you have
like this user surge of oil and you
haven't found it going deeper and deeper
and then finally you hit and it's like
this little bit of black starts pouring
up right you got your second drink and
you know dude yeah after a while a kiss
just [__] and then I hit the pocket yeah
and then all of a sudden yes you're
playing Johnny Cash in the touch tunes
yeah yeah yeah dude and I remember yeah
there's usually one point in with every
song that I write lyrically where I like
I hit that pocket and I write like a vs.
in like five seconds and it's just like
line after line after line and I'm like
yep that's [__] it that's it that's
all I needed to say and it all worked
out perfectly and it's sick I love when
that happens and then the only other
thing that I guess - like if we're
looking at the process is like with
metal and stuff like before the
breakdown happens you know there's that
punch line and that's like it's it's the
money shot like you know like in
important terms it's like it's the
[__] money shot
you're right you guys up in the air dude
yeah like it's got to be good you got to
send it so like that's the only other
thing is like I'll work around that too
it's like alright this is where the big
like this is like the lyric that like if
it had to go
on a [__] shirt would it sell this is
the lyric that like you know when when
you're playing it live and you hold the
mic out is the mic gonna be able to like
is the crowd gonna sing it back like
that you know it's like the big punch
line that's like it needs to be catchy
it needs to be something that people can
[__] get behind otherwise it's like
you know like it's not gonna be as good
which like our song family that was the
one thing this last year we just did
every date because that we also like
made a meme out of this breakdown and it
went viral and I think that helped a lot
too but the lyric is and this is right
before like the drop like the breakdown
the big part in the song and the lyric
it says take it back I don't want the
[__] anymore and so every night on tour
I'll go take it back in the crowd go I
don't want to [__] anymore how's that
feel it was [__] do you remember that
exact like were you at the bar for that
one do you remember oh yeah dude yeah
yeah I know yeah you want to break apart
that song I bawled like yeah it was
about like me and my brother we went
through like a pretty big rough patch
and it was stuff like that but then
other people in the band like we've all
had family issues you know I've had
problems with my dad and [__] like that
and the songs mainly just about how you
know like this is cliche but I don't
give a [__] you know like um how family
isn't always blood and you know like
it's the realest thing ever made yeah
yeah just yeah and just like you know
especially like being a musician and
like in a metal band you're on the road
with four other dudes who like dude
you're once you do a couple tours with
these guys like it they're they're like
kind of closer than family because they
you see each other at your highest highs
your lowest lows and there's no [__]
privacy or like it's all intimacy 24/7
yeah it's like good luck having a mask
like poor people yeah yeah so like one
beautiful thing that you guys would have
on stage because of that people yeah
having a few tours in your belt and
having a lot of tours on your belt now
yeah yeah like an even on stage it's
like you know it's it's so like
girlfriend [__] like it's like man what
the [__] would I do without these guys
you know like like that's how close you
get it's crazy and it's like yeah it's
it's a very intimate [__] strong bond
that I've
only felt through like being in a band
and [__] and it's it's it's great but
it's also it [__] sucks because it's
like it's like having four girlfriends
you know when it's good it's really good
when it's bad you got a you got a really
[__] now - yeah yeah you really got to
work on those conflict resolution skills
you really gotta [__] you know be
good and be patient with everyone you
know all right
but yeah it's that instigating you did
you get like so many I like the not
having space from someone would be
difficult for me like not being able
because I'm such a recharger dude like
you so I'm gonna van yeah man it's so
great that you guys are able to like
solve these things it's so cool because
it's I mean you said you're like not
intelligent but I mean your your
emotional intelligence
yeah I'm intelligent like emotionally
just not like books and like I mean okay
but I'm like that I've made so many good
videos you're a wonderful musician
you're great you're great salesman yeah
you're good at being on this podcast I'm
doing things are good at but I just I
think you're intelligent well thank you
yeah I just like I just meant like you
know like book smart like right told me
to spell this thing I'd be like I
[__] care no you you have you have
dove in it you know so so some people
are doctors and some people are lawyers
and some people dive into the pits the
soul of humanity and you help people
about it you know that's what you do
that's like people like it's a hard
[__] job but it's like eautiful yeah
if I wanted to go be an electrician or
if I wanted to go be something that
required like those skills like I
probably wouldn't be able to do it I
probably would fail the test because
that's what my brother's doing right now
he's he's being electrician like he told
me do yeah and but like he told me like
all the tests yeah did you do like just
get into like the program or all that
[__] and I was like yeah I definitely
would not have passed that at all and
like the homework he has to do and [__]
and I'm like nope like I did I literally
cannot do any well so you mean they
learn about it you're making this [__]
work wizard but yeah ventually though
you got to believe that it's coming I
mean either way it's it's funny because
as you get older you start to realize
it's like you're you are chasing money
and it would be great to have money but
you're like oh yeah this isn't my
[__] life though and it is pretty
cool even with like the currency that
you're getting
you know like having enough money to be
able to grab a six-pack on your way over
to like to talk to your buddy dude yeah
kind of sprays it's great yeah I
definitely and like you know I've worked
hard for like the things I have so it's
cool but like so like yeah all the
touring and stuff too like I remember we
broke down one time and we were at a
Ford dealership getting it fixed and of
course the guys like oh you own the band
I was like yeah and it was like dude
that's so sick
and I was like I mean look at us right
now dude we're [__] stranded and God
knows [__] where we've been driving
for 24 hours you still have another 24
hours to go just to play a show in front
of probably five kids and get paid a
hundred bucks and like just making our
way home like this isn't that [__]
sick dude for [__] that you do in to the
yes of your no I'll never forget this
because the guy said well I'll tell you
what I know everyone here we just talked
about and we'd much rather be doing what
you guys are doing right now than being
at the shitty [__] job and that
[__] cool
oh man that pulls you out of it what it
what a great perspective yeah I was just
like damn dude like yeah like if the
grass is never greener dude yeah wait
you know sometimes when it's shitty for
us where we look at the other side
because you know that's how it is being
like you know we can't go get a new car
we can't go [__] live in an expensive
place we can't go spend money because
like we have to spend it when we're on
tour and we like we don't make money on
the road so it's like we have to save
like we sacrifice a lot to do all that
[__] and like it's really hard
it's [__] very difficult but then to
hear someone like that be like I'll tell
you mean the guys in the office were
just talking and we'd [__] love to be
doing what you guys are doing and it's
like damn okay yeah that's it flip [__]
and it's after that day like it really
stuck with me and I was like I need to
like like don't take this [__] for
granted right yeah I think you guys are
doing it well I think you got to pick
your you got to pick your pains right
you got to like like so your pains are
either like being stressed out about
electrician tests or it's being
potentially strand on the side of the
road right yeah and like not knowing if
you're gonna pay rent or all right I
know and if you're gonna have a house to
come home to or but it feels like it's
worth it right at times yeah yeah yeah
yeah it definitely is and there's also
like with music and you know sports and
a lot of professions there's there's a
big part of putting in your Jesus and
it's just [__] you know that you got to
do and that's what I tell a lot of young
musicians like the big whenever
someone's like so I get asked on like
podcasts and stuff a lot like what
advice you'd give like a young musician
and it's my first thing and I don't
think I've ever heard anyone say this
and I wish I got this advice it is uh
learn to eat [__] and learn to love it
because that's what your first [__]
years are gonna be it's gonna be you're
eating [__] except it make the best out
of the [__] and just learn to [__]
love it it'll make life way [__]
easier like just learn to love the [__]
they'll - [__] sculpture dude yeah
exactly pretty given acne and you know I
guess that's why I like shits poppin off
cuz you know with this band we've never
looked at like what could we have or
like oh if we had this we never bitched
about anything we're just like alright
well they don't want to do this for us
so we're gonna go do it ourselves or we
have this let's go do it with this you
know you can't you can't you can't sit
here and wish like you had that or you
know like you just you can only work
with the cards you dealt and especially
in music starting out you're not gonna
have a good deck of cards ever for
probably your first five years unless
your post Malone which you're not [__]
post Malone that's like a one in five
you know yeah yeah yeah but like videos
dude yeah and but I mean still like he
didn't have to like go to her for
[__] tenure right right
people really think there's like this
there has been a couple people who are
the one-hit wonders right like overnight
they have like a tick tock video or
Instagram and all sudden they have like
contracts and all this [__] yeah but
like people think that that is like you
have a high it's a high percentage of
that happening no yeah and that's the
other thing and with post Fallone I use
them in as an example too because like
he surpassed all that he had the he
white Iverson was the one hit and it's
like okay you're either going up or down
from here now yeah and he went up he did
Stoney which was great followed it up
and it followed it up again and now he's
at the point where it's like you know he
can't go backwards now right he's so you
know it yeah dude I think that his
remember Fetty WAP where the [__] is
that guy now
I think on the radio like Texas again I
saw him I saw him laugh and it was it
was normally known how recently it was
years ago it was a it was one of the
bumper shoots a few years back I thought
it was not good but but dude a a crazy
thing about post Malone you know I look
at so like my name is J Lee's
relationship we literally just like lay
on the couch we'll watch post Mon
interviews and videos together he's such
a cool guy he's I think that you know
the why diverse in the song first his
first few songs whatever like the songs
aside I think he's popular because he's
so genuine or and that's why I say
you're not [__] post Malone because
that is the dude if you look at that
dude's career and what happened you know
how many [__] stars were aligned for
all that to happen it was a little bit
of a luck it was a lot of him being
genuine it was so many [__] things
out there you can't duplicate those
results dude and so you're gonna have to
go slave away in a van you know even
[__] Justin Bieber had to do that
well in you know Justin Bieber wasn't an
overnight sensation like a lot of people
think he was but yeah dude he was
playing good acoustic guitar on this
dude yeah and he toured radio stations
from water parks and played in front of
40 kids for the first year of his career
yep I love Justin Bieber I love it
so origin story let's back up a little
bit so what have you been into music
your whole life what did you when you
get into it I played my first show when
I was like 13 so yeah it's been a long
time would you play what song can you
remember uh uh dive was in a band played
guitar yeah and I was in it was my older
brother he was a drummer at the time and
he was like hey you want to come you
know you like I know you could like kind
of play guitar like you want to come be
in a band I was like [__] it dude let's
go and then that's when I just kind of
fell in love with it and I was like this
shit's tight and then yeah did that
really awful band with my brother for a
little bit I was 13 like you know what
the [__] it's not gonna be good yeah
yeah trying to be good and then I like I
joined like my first like decent band
when I was 16 that was in longview did
my no no when I was 15 we did my first
tour I was 15 with that band and then
from that band started my band that I
was in before dead crown called we rise
of tides [__] terrible scene name but
that band got that's kind of well like
put me on the map like in our scene that
dan because we put out a record that did
like pretty well regionally and then
like that's when like my social meetings
and stuff sort of like pumping up and to
this day like I don't get someone in the
crowd heckling like plea we Rose the
toads I'll be like you [__] [__]
no [__] yeah [__] you who do you think
is it is it dallas green from seed in
color that was in asking alexandria now
here yeah yeah dallas green what if
they're like in there he's just like
singing like just super soft
yeah city in color play [__] so far he's
like dude I'll [__] kill you yeah
just like a security can you [__] take
care of this guy he pulled me other zone
I'm done yeah but no it's fine and like
that that doesn't happen very often like
one of the dudes that did heckle he like
afterwards he like he came and bought a
bunch of merchants like took a picture
he's like I'm so sorry about that comet
like I just love tides I've been
following you ever since so all those
people from that time like they still
follow me now crowds even explore crowds
for a second let's take a deeper so
you've probably experienced some
different sides of crowds that I have so
I completely different [__] worlds
and I want to talk to you about this too
because we are from like different music
scenes and yeah we are I mean so I've I
have you know I've been to plenty of
pretty pretty hard shows like I don't
know I probably haven't been to
obviously like nowhere near your field
of course no I've seen like suicide boys
and stuff you know they are oh yeah yeah
yeah I mean I heard their shows kind of
pop off like metal shows yeah it's
pretty rad he's pretty much metal show I
mean and I've been when I was you know
14 15 I was going every Warped Tour and
I know it's Warped Tour but like [__]
yeah that's where dude yeah that's where
that [__] happened yeah yeah I remember
[__] seeing a mirror and seeing
people [__] die in that mosh pit dude
okay you know like dude I got a car a
couple years back me and my friend Tyler
went we're like T we got to go to one
more like let's just do it and we got we
just got hammered we just said yes to
everything and we we marched at Waka
Flocka Flame I got kicked in the [__]
face and I was like the best day of my
life and so hey it was just so fun but
so okay so crowds like they are
definitely very different let's let's
talk about what would you say is a
difference like this I mean I would say
for metal it's way harder to pull a
crowd but honestly I don't know that
because I've been to some pretty [__]
shot rap shows but talking to you I
remember like when I made that video for
you about the day
and you did the the [__] that show
out in the middle of the goddamn woods
and we were going up to it like this is
how like I didn't know what the [__]
your world was because I was like hey
dude cuz you didn't post it publicly or
anything so I hate you up I remember
even like the renegade yeah yeah but I
remember hitting you up and being like
dude how are you like promoting the show
cuz I was like dude there's gonna be no
one [__] here
there's no promo for it like I don't
want to go shoot this video and like
he's gonna want me to film [__] like
there's gonna be [__] awkward like
I'm and I was like are well whatever
it's his [__] he'll to die on and you
were like I'll just snap snap chat and
buy only my world can't [__] do that
there will be no one [__] there you
got a really push and then I show up to
this [__] renegade [__] back was a
party thing and it's the most lit [__]
[__] ever there's like probably like
300 people there it was so fun yeah wow
so sick dude I don't know how they just
I started doing those other people so
other people down in Portland started
doing him and I would go to those in in
an I like I knew a couple of people
there were some things that went really
right yeah me I have like an event
planner like I'm the same way yeah so so
I'm like what could I do differently and
so yeah so I started doing my own and
like we it would be cool it's
essentially for me and my heart it is
the it is the Pacific Northwest like my
like electronic version of the renegade
warehouse part it's where you don't get
the address to the day of and this is
what it was like we've had like and you
could you could see like when I showed
up I was like damn that's a lot of word
of mouth yeah done and that's that's
honestly the sickest thing to have
because if you are able to build that
like that's a hard hype to build to wear
like somewhat you you give an address a
day of and someone's like I am telling
all my [__] friends and we are going
to this 10 night like that's a hard
[__] thing when you start to build a
little reputation like I had you know I
probably done like at the lender ten of
them and we would book at six DJs and
it'd be like you know the date and you
know that it's in this county yeah and
then what is just like you have to get
in on the circle yeah yeah did and
that's six hours and that's probably
some of the magic to it but like so the
on the flip side and like my world like
we just did our CD release Sheila
Hawthorne I was like 350 paid and we had
to promote that for two months hard like
annoy the
[__] out of people promote and and like
a tickets flew the last week
like you know in especially in Portland
Northwest like in that I guess our scene
like people just procrastinate a lot but
it's like dude god damn that's so
[__] stressful if you're gonna go to
something buy your [__] tickets early
because there's people like me on the
other line waiting to see oh my god I
hope people show up to my [__] show
and then the day of they're like oh yeah
you guys it's like [__] killed it
like it was almost 400
the show was [__] lit it was like wow
I wish I would have known this like it's
that is gonna go this well like a couple
weeks ago I know because you have all
that nervousness and here we have a
stress okay it's weird because nobody
seems to be able to commit to something
we're just talking yeah yeah yeah and
then also the side note like this is
that Hawthorne so like if the show
flopped that was like it was you paid
that was our house see yeah that's
something that like and we usually make
a lot of money when we play our hometown
shows and this is our first time doing
Hawthorne so we're like dude if this
doesn't go good
yeah like [__] how much cakewalk I have
like compared to what what you go
through like a lot dude you know I'm
like obviously I have my [__] of
course we all do but it's crazy you know
it's it's it's just like it's so cool
because you're like you know this [__]
this is gonna be super hard but this is
what is pouring out of me this is the
oil that's coming out I got it I got to
do it it's dude yeah but and I guess
that's the other thing like I don't know
about you oh that's the other thing I
remember back when we were doing this
video and stuff you were telling me you
were like I DJ you DJ and silver star
then mmm okay yeah and you told me that
they paid you like a pretty handsome
[__] amount for that [__] and like
you didn't have to promote it all no and
I was like really you don't have to like
pre sell tickets you know if they're
doing that and they're giving you that
much pretty much every gig that I've
ever done I keep it pretty much that
level I don't dude okay it's not that
way at all
I [__] [__] my pants I was like and
you did you you that all that money goes
to you because you're a DJ yeah like I
will say the way I look at setting the
stage for this yeah I have like high
school popularity that I stayed in the
same town and I rode that high school
popularity so like and you draw Matt
here anybody who books me around or like
in it was starting to go a little
Vancouver Portland some some Seattle
shows
had friends you know whatever but it was
like we're gonna book him and we already
know that we get 30 people with him so
it's like that that's enough for anyway
if I was to live it in town and like you
were DJing there I'd be like [__] yeah
go [__] hang out Jake in and you know
and it's something again like a work
really hard to keep exactly yeah yeah
yeah I [__] you know I I try to make
sure that I'm worth yeah worth what I'm
bringing in but it is awesome but yeah
but like from my world it's like who'll
do like it it took us well I didn't take
dead crown necessarily a while cuz we we
were pretty smart about our finances and
like our [__] and stuff but like my
older bands like dude it was years of
pushing tickets pre-selling before I
figured [__] out and like we were worth
enough as [__] to a learn to run our own
shows so there's no promoter taking all
their [__] money and then like just
figuring it all out too so that now
we're in a position where it's like we
play Portland we're walking away with
quite a bit of [__] money you know
and and that's good especially for like
that's the other thing like being in a
touring band and like a metal band like
dude there's so many expensive so like
we have a van we have a trailer we have
maintenance on those things
well what about everything back home
like how do you like when you're on tour
so much and it's like I got to pay my
bills back home safe it's everyday job
but the band doesn't pay for any of that
of course the band only pays for itself
because then and then it will like we
like so for this last tour we did when
the day of our CD release show after I
paid all the bills and stuff was like
hey guys we have $11 on our [__]
PayPal account yeah yes and we were like
sick and then it was like alright well
we better do good this to her played six
shows came home with about four grand so
that's good
that's very good and we are [__] I
will say right now as a metal band we
are very [__] blessed to be in that
situation yeah there are a lot of metal
bands that do that and we [__]
thankfully we've like but that's the
thing we do really well on merch and
stuff it merch is a big hitter like
these this windbreaker sold out at like
two days who do you design the merch
dude yeah yeah that's the other thing
yeah but um so but but then like when we
get home like we have all this money and
then it's like you sit there and you're
like oh yeah but we have to pay this
there's this after that merger was done
and that
getting ready for this tour and all that
and it's gone again you know so it's
like and you only have enough for one
double vodka soda well doing writing
lyrics yeah well that's what I mean like
dude the band no one and the band gets a
paycheck from the band itself like we're
not at that level yet where we can start
doing pay outs well and then even even
the complications of you know like in
the future of things yeah 401k and
retirement all that crap oh dude I was
just talkin it just gets ya I was just
talking to someone the other day I was
like yeah I work for myself and I'm an
artist I don't have a 401k and I
probably never will so I don't think I'm
ever gonna retire I'm probably just
gonna be yeah me at the [__] Walmart
customer I'll be the guy [__] greeting
you on the way out of Walmart you know
what I'm [__] 7000 hey dude there's a
kid there's a couple guys that I like
recognize from the Walmarts in our towns
and generally make me happy because
they're just happy they're perfect for
that job because they're just happy
dudes like they just eat and [__] and
learn to love it yeah so so jumping back
to guess the difference is the crowd so
okay you're drawing crowds definitely I
think the biggest difference is
obviously your honor of music like it's
yeah that's a huge difference it's I
mean like let's let's call like it is
it's a popular music that everything
yeah yes it's the exact way like I'm not
like I'm not [__] on on what I do
because I love what I do now no no
obviously but exactly yeah but it's it
is way easier like the fact that you
guys [__] scrape your faces through
nails to play these shows it's just so
greatest says so much about the art and
so much like like you guys man it's just
I just keep thinking about this 15 16
year old kid who I'm listening to
people's lyrics and like oh like you
guys can have 15 six-year-old kids who
are getting through their [__] you
know who are yeah whatever after this
last hour yeah it's so worth yeah this
last album it did really but we just put
out like [__] oh yeah earlier this
month house name it's called crucify me
okay but it did really well and like
we're starting to see the most just like
general outpour of support that we've
ever gotten like beyond like just like
before it was like oh yeah I kind of
know that guy now just like complete
strangers in boxes getting hit
like the coolest thing the other day our
pre-order bundles showed up to people's
houses so like all day we were just
getting social media like messages
public orders I got my [__] dead
crown pre-order bundle up taking selfies
in it some girls were like really
[__] hot pictures of and they're like
look at my [__] dead crown really
it's like [__] yeah but they were like
and it's also like cuz it's like I guess
it's coming out like close to Christmas
and so I mean I don't know if it's time
of year that did it but seeing all that
[__] was like it was a really [__]
cool thing and like we've never really
had that experience before where it's
like you know there's complete strangers
who like mail day came and they got our
[__] and they were like so [__]
stoked about it that they're like cool
on the internet like got my [__] dead
crown [__] oh and like we we loved it it
was so sick so then we were like yo keep
it coming like yo who else got their
viewers like let us know we want to see
that [__] yeah and so all day like the
last couple days just been [__] people
blasting that [__] and it's been such a
[__] cool feeling and it's been very
like the the biggest thing about all
this [__] is like it's so [__]
humbling and just like it may I can
almost feel guilty cuz it's like I feel
like these people are doing like so many
cool things for me and it's like I'm not
doing anything for you give back but I
know that's not how it works you know
it's like it's it's just weird I because
I've especially a metal and stuff when
you're up and you're coming up on this
grind like the biggest thing the worst
thing to do is be like I got [__]
fans no [__] you got friends
that come to your [__] shows right
you know you got like it's rappers -
yeah dude and it's like it's like you
don't got [__] fans until like I'd
like that's what we're starting to
experience now it's like oh this is like
having fans like I don't know these
people and I feel like I owe them
something but they don't want anything
for me they just love what we [__] do
so it's a whole new experience in like
emotional thought process for me but
it's like the coolest [__] thing and
I just like when I say like I love you
all and like just thank you so much for
all the [__] like that actually I'm just
like thank you so much for like [__]
with this [__] like spanning spending
might like dude there are so many people
that bought like our hundred dollar
[__] pre-order package it's just like
you spent $100 on my [__] bin dude
and it's like and you trace it back and
this is this is literally because of me
having this that happened when I was
seven and I wrote about it last year and
you yeah
it's been great it's been a crazy month
man crazy about this whole album and
like it's a really good we charted on
Billboard again we had 450,000 streams
our first week like it's just been
[__] like we're all just like whoa
what's happening like are we becoming
like a real band kind of yeah yeah and
then like dude like um like we're get
like a band like that I [__] love and
like draw a lot of influence from like
hit us up on Instagram was like hey we
[__] love you guys uh we want to take
you out on tour and like now we're like
about to go like we're away yeah okay oh
wait can you can you see the banner is
it released yet um it's no okay so I'll
say it here they're called Lionheart
okay and and they're they're like a
they're like kind of like an OG hardcore
band but they like yeah they hit us up
on Instagram or like you like cuz
they're from Sacramento they're like we
you just they really sent out just just
this month - so they're like yo we [__]
with you guys basically and like what's
your guys is tour schedule like we want
to take you guys out just do a little
West Coast run with you guys oh he's
sick and I was like yeah dude and like
you know we've gotten like crazy amounts
of like tour offers already and [__]
some that like something I like
definitely aren't good and stuff but
like it's looking like 2020 is gonna be
like oh we're actually out on like real
tours I mean being able to have offers
and choose from them know like hey yeah
that's sick
yeah and this is like kind of the first
time that I've been in that situation so
I'm just trying to like just be [__]
humble and grateful about it and just be
like you know and I always that's and
I'm a weird person like I feel like I
don't deserve a lot of these things and
I always trouble with that too yeah III
downplay myself a lot and I'm just like
dude like it's not that [__] cool
like and but it's also like what keeps
my [__] head on straight and it makes
things like not go to my head yeah
because I I never want to be that guy
that like no watch out for that ego man
yeah and I've always been like I've seen
other people like that I'm just like
your [__] [__] like I never want
to be like that and like and and also
like what I see in those people is they
just seemed so like not in touch with
reality and like that scares me too
it's not that like I don't care if you
think I'm a douchebag or not I don't
want to be out of touch with my [__]
reality did you watch the Elton John
Rocket Man movie do you know I need to
see that though yeah you would enjoy
essentially it's it's kind of like it
shows kind of him being reckless
throughout his life yeah other he kind
of realizes whatever it's kind of like
that like you've got to be aware and a
lot of musicians have gone through so
much [__] you know and that's what gives
the beauty to the beauty and the the
awesomeness to their lyrics you know but
it did yeah if they if I haven't handled
it or their lyrics aren't really a way
for them to handle what they're writing
is it yeah a lot of times it's just
covered and and that's the other thing
like difference in worlds once again
that's you don't see a lot of that in
metal music
what do you mean like recklessness and
and people like except for like back
when you know like I would say like the
thrash metal days were kind of like the
last of it you'll hear of like a dude
like having [__] heroin problem here
and there and stuff but you never it's
because like the fame it's not even Fame
like you even if you get really big in
this metal world you're still not as big
as that Elton John never will they say
you can still go to the [__] Walmart
and just walk through but you're big in
a different world a thing like exactly
types of and it's it's a wavelength yeah
and it's a way smaller world but that's
the thing the fame isn't so excess where
it [__] with your head I feel like it's
very manageable which is kind of good
and it's a slow burn there's not a lot
of bands that like just blow the [__] up
overnight and metal and stuff a lot of
them have been grinding for a long time
they've been able to be like assured
into it a little bit and like it's not
just such a harsh like hey you're
[__] famous now right now like what
do you think about like the is so like I
think a little I mean I don't know
specifically but say to let's say a
little pump yeah like he's someone who's
like overnight success of these like
rappers like dude yeah he's reckless the
future of these guys I feel like it's
like you know the next five years is
gonna like in five years their heads are
gonna be [__] me well yeah whole life
Justin Bieber is almost on that he was
almost [__] right he was on that path
of self-destruction and thankfully he
had some people around him I feel that
you know kind of helped him be like yo
dude he like kind of stopped being a
[__] idiot out to the family of the B
yeah dude yeah and and just imagine if
he didn't have that and he kept going
down that road that's what I mean like
yeah
when you get that famous that quick you
are not in touch with reality I don't
think it's great it's no it's really not
it's in like like you know when you're
14 that's so terrible
locked in reckless behaviors when I was
14 I got out of out of just my life and
whatever and I didn't turn them off I
didn't realize that I hadn't done them
off and you're like when we were 14 and
stuff when we were being reckless we
didn't have millions of [__] dollars
we couldn't do whatever the [__] we
wanted so imagine just being like hey
here's the keys to do whatever the [__]
you want your office and also hold a
camera while you're doing it so yeah
having more cool gay yeah and everyone's
watching you which is great it's like
yeah you got a big fan base but that's
the other thing with our culture
nowadays you slip up you do one [__]
thing wrong you're [__] done you're
cancelled you know this a platforming
[__] people just feel like it's like
it's like we're walking around like hey
you're you're wearing your perfect hat
right okay I mean yeah and yeah we all
know we're not perfect but we can't talk
about it
[__] weird oh [__] dude yeah and so
let's talk about the you know the
culture from I want to talk about let's
say all right we got sixty five-year-old
Carol she's never been to a metal show
but our narrow you yeah her nephew or
not her nephew her grandson yeah yeah he
likes metal he's 16
between the ages of 16 and 20 yeah for
sure she knows that he loves it but she
thinks it's [__] crazy and she
doesn't understand it yes it's probably
a really common thing can you lighten
her heart a little bit can you explain
all like if it Kara was like in here
right now and I'd to like tell her yeah
hey I'm concerned about my kid going
your show seems is it devil-worshipping
music no I will say hey I [__] if it
wasn't for this crazy like music world I
live and I probably would be dead right
now right so caroled like a lot of
people find this for the best reasons
and they end up in this weird metal of
like this weird world of metal probably
for the best reasons ever because you
know it isn't land of the misfit so it's
the land of the [__] rejects that you
know got cast out we're [__] cool to
do that and like they're [__] weird
for liking it but there's so much that's
the biggest thing I love about metal is
like it is its own little [__] world
and it's a small world
but it's our [__] world we have our
own culture within it and it's like no
one else ever
and understands it and when you're a
part of that and you're at one of those
shows and you're like in that metal
culture that's nothing else is like it
you can sit there be in that moment
people would be like there's nothing
else in this world like this and this is
ours this is an hour I think that it you
know it gives purpose to like so so many
things it's so sick and it's such a
relief to of young kids like for me my
my thing this last year for like getting
my like oh my energy might like I'm
going crazy yeah I got to go out and ID
like trail running or hiking or
something that myself and a lot of times
when I was younger dude it was going to
shows and thrash and like yeah it's
sometimes it's like man I got this
pent-up energy and I don't really
understand it my parents won't
understand it because we don't know the
same things yeah yeah I do know that
when I walk out of these shows when I
walk out of dip crouch so I feel super
great dude yeah that's yeah that's it
important dude ya know and that's that's
what metal is for like so many people
and like it's dude yeah it's it's a
crazy little [__] up world but it is
it's our world and if you're lucky
enough to like be a part of it and be
fully submerge in it like you know every
metal people but so I don't know it's
hard to explain man like it's its own
world it's its own culture and like only
it's like a secret underground club like
you only know if you know yeah you know
it's funny because it's it's you see it
as like a culture that's completely
you're like okay I get it I have a
culture that's my music it's country or
whatever yeah and we're like this but
yours is nothing like ours but it's like
you ever seen someone in a mosh pit get
hit hit on the ground then everybody's
like making sure they get up yeah like I
mean there there is a family vibe 2.oh
yeah do to your metal show - exactly yes
it's just a different cool it just it's
just different yeah it's just it's it's
almost counterculture you know like in
some ways except for now it's getting a
little more you know like you know
you'll see people and [__] name brands
and you know some people want to flex
that's mainly on the musician side of
things you don't really see fans like
wearing [__] Gucci and [__] so
off-brand Russia you know that's a cool
thing most metal most actually yeah I'm
a [__] idiot about most metal fans
are wearing [__] metal rich that they
bought from bands will just tightest
[__] oh yeah people are showing up in
their dead crowned shirts that are shows
and it's like [__] yeah thank you for
buying that from us yeah you're helping
us pay the [__] bills when the
[__] like that's sick [__] yeah and
you decide to Kindle I did
okay so so wait I want to we talk a lot
about dead crown in the culture
obviously but I do want to talk about
you yeah yeah yeah and yeah you're a
wonderful person man I met you a long
time ago do we meet was it through pacts
okay yeah and actually I want to give
yeah so PacSun because my first boss
ever was Shaylee your your lovely
girlfriend thank you boo thing yeah and
huge shout out to Shaylee because that
actually did a lot for me in life yeah
dude I was 16 it was my first job ever
so first of all like I got the best
first bosses in the world
Shaylee and Emily were like the best
like they set me up to where like I went
to other jobs and I was like these
people higher above me are [__] at what
they do because Shane Lee
Shaylee and Emily were just they're the
best [__] bosses you can have they
they showed me a lot of things they were
[__] patient they were they weren't
[__] like just like you know you you
get everyone has like a shitty boss
experience with them it was like they
showed me like what a boss should be
yeah and like I'm so thankful I had that
experience but then also you know like
when I started working at PacSun and
kills the longview it was like oh you're
working with those girls huh you know
they're beautiful young girls and like
every girl here in popular girls and
growing up I got up and down by a lot of
girls I was never sought after I was not
you know I didn't have all the
girlfriends and [__] so Shaylee and
Emily like in a weird fucked-up way they
were the first kind of like cool
beautiful girls to say yes to me and be
like come hang with us
and stuff and before I you know I was
always the weird like I grew up in a
really small town like 30 kids in my
class and like I was like considered fat
my class like I was a chubby it was
[__] weird and I'll get up and often
down a lot like the [__] is he wearing
I had a curly [__] Harry Knowles
[__] now just a weird kid but they
were yourself in a bridge but you know I
did two interviews and like you know
they were the first people to be like
yeah say those are the like that was my
first experience with like you know cool
beautiful girls saying like yes
me that's crazy do you think that if you
had to remember back do you think that
you went into the interview like how
great like these are the popular girls
we're not gonna like I mean do you think
that you had me I was definitely nervous
about that yeah I was worried about that
the way I have that yeah yeah I was
worried that like but it ended up not
being that way and then obviously like
working him like with Shaylee and Emily
they were to the [__] like best
people I've ever met
yeah dude I I mean I was awesome this is
all what like what's exception of like
my girlfriend careth oh my god of course
well you know like she would she you
know she said yes to me first like love
her but of course you know yeah you go
where I'm saying yeah of course yeah no
and I appreciate that and don't make
sure that she leave notice yeah but that
ended a lot for me and like she was
awesome and she also helped me like
break that stereotype to of like you
know you know here's he's like really
you know popular girls I'm really just
gonna really [__] tell me to get out
of here and like you know ya know give
me time of day they're gonna make me
feel small one way yeah yeah and then
they did the complete opposite yeah they
were they were awesome and then I
remember you came in you you also
changed it to you came in you had an
extra drink and I was just like oh
that's Jake like he's pretty [__]
cool I'm like I'm just as nerdy [__] kid
working for his girlfriend and you were
like hey I got an extra drink you want
it you know like I usually always bring
one for whoever Chili's working with and
I was like really
dad dude you brought me a drink and I
was like that was cool [__] and you're
like hey how you doing and you're like
nice as [__] to me you know it's not
used to that from like you know popular
kids you know I never had that so that
was really [__] cool you know so
crazy is is I know now like you know
popularity like popularity is such a
weird thing but it's where we have to
use you know when yeah yeah I live in a
small area but you see so in that
situation I don't remember that I
probably was like hoping that you
thought that I was cool I don't know I
know dude it's so crazy I do that it's
like this like invisible barrier now you
can even say like I'm on that up
opposite side too because I know that
like you know there's there's a lot of
people out there that think like my
bands like way bigger than what it is
you know they don't understand you know
so like I'm i-i've noticed like I'm in
conversation sometimes where it's like
wow I'm really intimidating this guy and
I'm not meaning to and you know just
because like oh yeah he thinks I'm in
this like huge band like you know dude I
have this conversation with a couple of
DJ guys that I know I think we mentioned
on the podcast about
when when you have a creative job or
when you have a job that's like a
passion yeah
when other people tell you about their
job they feel the need to downplay and I
hate that so so for example like if
someone knows that I'm a DJ and I'm like
talking about that and I ask about them
and they're go I'm just a bank teller
yeah it's you're more than a bank teller
but yeah it's I hate how we just like
signify our jobs yeah yeah yeah I know
and and I kind of do that about myself
because I yeah like yeah when people ask
me I'm just like no I'm just plain a man
like it's not as glamorous as you think
it is you know like I try to like
because like I could just be a huge
they'd be like I'm gonna [__]
band-aid you know I'm [__] yeah it's
pretty sick we [__] char on there we
[__] you know like yeah but it's like
it's like no it's not that [__]
luxurious like you know like I'm still
not [__] like it's it's you know I'm
doing good I'm proud of myself but it's
like to the outside you know people I'm
just running into like I would never go
up to [__] you and be like yeah dude
I'm doing like the sick [__] Rashmi yeah
yeah it's just like no like I'm doing
all right
like you know I love what I do and I
just I just play music and the other
thing is like I'm also like I just feel
like anyone could do if they wanted to
oh my god was able to do it like oh if
you want you go do it dude
yeah you know that's what I feel about
everyone you just practice yeah you just
kinda like just gotta eat [__] and learn
to love it and you can do anything you
know yeah okay so so you do a lot of a
couple years ago you mentioned you did a
video for me in the video is super dope
yeah yeah yeah first starting out with
video 2 so a day was good again though I
like I have so many more like spells and
tricks now oh we have some things to
talk about after this okay but so you do
a lot of video work you do a lot of
merch work design work yeah what else do
you do what what else like so yeah graph
designs like my main thing and a lot of
people like they just see my music
videos and stuff so they're like no you
just make a flow down a music videos
like no I like probably do like one a
month so like that's not like my main
like many major but a lot of its gravity
is like so and primarily in the music
industry I've tried to break into the
corporate world but it didn't work out
and I'm blessed because making it in the
music
industry anything's really hard so yeah
for the last four or five years I've
been full-time doing design in the music
industry and so yeah I like design like
logos merchandise uh you know like the
packaging for like CDs and stuff like
that
how'd you learn all this excuse me us
all self-taught oh uh yeah I had this
when I when I went to school in Catholic
I am high school we had a graphics class
total [__] joke of a class way
outdated software just I learned nothing
Windows 95 yeah I learned nothing about
design and anything and I remember I had
a [__] like a CD that I got from a
band at a show went to my teacher I was
like how do I make [__] like this and he
just goes I don't [__] know oh no so
I was like I was like okay and then I
heard the Internet
that night I went home and cracked
Photoshop and [__] just started like
alright let's start figuring this [__]
out held how old were you think that was
when I was 14 13 14 years old I think 14
the 14 or 15 Cutex I was in high school
dude I remember I for me when I first
broke into music I was like a pirate
that software and figure it out maybe
yeah it's so Ableton so I had a friend
who over in Florida who I had worked
with into me he was yeah like this gene
I'm like dude if there's somebody who
knows how to do it I had just got a
laptop like two years before I didn't
know anything much so that I remember
the first laptop I started doing design
with it was a two hundred dollar Toshiba
piece of [__] the thing was probably
heavy clouds Louis dude like now like
I'm pissed if like my MacBook Pro
doesn't fire up Photoshop in like less
than a minute back then I imagine video
editing on that thing do I remember back
in the day I would sit I would wake up
early because it would take 30 minutes
for everything to stops like startup so
I'd have to start it and then like go
shower go do all that [__] and then be
like sit down and work and then it'd
take me like eight hours to do we would
never back then we get so used to [__]
like that we would never come like we
didn't really complain like this is how
it is this is how computer sorry I was
thinking about that when you look at
like a 4k TV now dude yeah and you look
at a cheap one you're like this is a
piece of [__] TV three years ago you
thought that was the craziest - yeah
some point our eyes were gonna explode I
think yeah I like this too much dude
yeah but also it was like it was also
just I guess the grind and the
willingness
like I was just like well I want to
figure this out and I really liked it
some of the same with you in music
you're like no matter how long it took
for the software load or how many
crashes you had to deal with because
your computer was a piece of [__] you
were still just like well fire back up
and let's go again because I love this
and I want to figure it out so cool it's
so cool yeah and like passionate about
it yeah and that's and that's the other
thing like I knew so many kids like in
high school that would say to me like oh
like I think it's so cool that you're
doing this so I'm like doing what and
they're like you're following like your
passions you're doing what you want to
do and I'll be like aren't you doing
that like oh I just have to go dude okay
I get that and I don't know what to say
oh man I'm like do you think you like I
like yeah thanks but also like no [__]
that you should look like if you're
passionate morning yeah that's how I
encourage everybody to like yes because
dude it's because when we look back and
talk about this now it's like yeah it no
all that [__] that I went through with
like those computers all that stuff and
never felt like a hassle or work at all
because I was yeah I'm sure the same
thing for you yeah exactly figuring it
all out you know like it was never as
never work whistle what's your view on
like the 10,000 hours which what is that
so 10,000 hours it's like the artists
from Africa who officially says it but
it's like if you want to be a master at
something you have to put in 10,000
hours I mean he's probably not [__]
wrong I mean unless you're a [__]
prodigy but again it's back to the post
Milan saying like you're not well can we
ever get that there's like a conscious
in a subconscious and we have to train
your subconscious that's running 90% of
you're at 95% your program all day you
have to train that [__] to be
good at guitar not the 5% that's here
right now like dude yeah yeah yeah it's
sad I just [__] the grind in it and
do it yet I mean did you do guitar
mainly when you first started was it
yeah yeah I was yeah I play guitar until
that we rise the tides man then I was
like [__] this I'm gonna be a frontman
cuz I was like what was that transition
like his you know when I was on guitar I
was so [__] like gave me all the
attention like stage [__] guy yeah so
that was like what did you sing also I
did like screams but we were like clean
there we had like a front man who likes
saying right I can't really sing very
good so I just hoot and holler and do
all that [__] but I was like I was just
so high energy and so like wanted to
work a crowd that was like I was fine
that is a art III not to [__] like
brag you're very good at it I
that's not ideal yeah yeah and like I've
I've been told by a lot of people like
dude you're like one of the best
frontman like in like this metal game
I've seen and I'm like thank you but I
definitely worked really hard it's so
like crowd control crowd psychology like
I'm really in all that [__] I love love
working a crowd I love getting a room of
[__] people and being like in ten
minutes you guys are all gonna be in the
palm of my hand and we're all gonna
[__] be vibin together do you have
strings on your kicks man you just
woohoo best feeling in this [__]
world is when you get a whole room and
you say everyone [__] jump at a
certain time you count it down you hype
it up it's the biggest thing and the
whole [__] floor is moving when you
say trust me I got you I got you I just
do it just do it into me in that crowd
and just in to put all your trust in
that it's okay as soon as I got a taste
for that that was like a whole other
pastors like yep I need to be a frontman
in a [__] metal man and that's what I
did how did you start training your
voice because this is there's a lot to
go into that I mean I just yeah it was
actually then Sevenfold [__] waking
the fallen shadows and shads dude yeah
yeah but me my brother we [__] love
that and my brother was like dude you
should start like figuring out how to do
that and I was like okay and then like
yeah what was your living situation when
you started screaming
I've lived with my parents look I was 13
did they really enjoy that no my parents
my parents were supportive but
definitely like looking back at it like
like they were probably just like god
[__] damn it dude cuz we sucked man
you know like dude you gotta suck though
thank you you had to miss a bunch of my
parents were supportive and like they
might have not liked it but like it
wasn't like I'm seeing commercials
nowadays on TV like advertising things
that are like I can't remember the
[__] commercial it was like a bunch
of kids jamming in a garage and like
they were really bad obviously like
everyone's [__] first band in a
garage is you got to figure that [__]
out but they're like it was like a
commercial to like block that out and
like not have to deal with it for some
product I can't remember what it is but
it was like I remember singing and I was
like that's very bad like that's that's
it's me really wrong like I don't really
like you know I let's let's stick right
here because I actually want to have
something that I'm going
through I'm like the last year so I'm
really processing a lot of my childhood
traumas yeah yeah and I'm trying to be
out loud about it in something that I'm
realizing is and if the wrong person
hears this I would hate for their
feelings to be hurt so don't take it the
wrong way listener if it's the wrong
person yeah I didn't I'm realizing that
when I was young I didn't have anybody
who told me liked who believed in me I
didn't have anybody told you believe in
myself if I wanted to be smart if I want
to be creative I got made fun of I got
poked fun if I got caught okay I got
called weird all these things so a lot
of my like my person my soul wants to
just express myself feel like I'm an
artist just walking I just want to I'm a
paintbrush to this world I feel like but
I have a lot of I get in front of a mic
and I'm like I don't who the [__] am i
and I don't have self-confidence because
I'm unwinding these things from when I
was younger you know and then you know
life happens and it's hard too hard you
get pressed down but so I think that the
insane importance of telling a kid or
telling a young person even an adult to
though yeah yeah like to to like it's
okay to suck Jackie - Miska goddamn
basketball shot yeah it's okay to play
off-key yeah dude yeah and thankfully
like answer so this wasn't when I was
playing music but when I was doing
sports cuz my dad he played college
football my dad was really into sports I
was probably supposed to be I I think I
broke my dad's heart when I completely
stopped playing sports and pursued music
honestly but when I was growing up I did
get that from my dad with sports I would
have all these crazy dreams of like how
I want to be in the NBA oh I want to be
in the NFL like dad do you think I could
do it you always say you can do anything
you put your mind to hell yeah he always
said that to me
but just for sports when I got into
music I wasn't really seeking that but
he you know but he instilled that in me
at a young age so I carried it over like
I got it no it did it did carry over and
like dude there's times where like I'm
so so she like dude like just not to
like go all around but like there's
there's times like when we're you roll
up to a venue and it's like tonight's
crowds gonna be shot mm-hmm and you know
it I know it going into it and being
this metal frontman I'm supposed to you
know whether there's you know there's
five people and I got to sit there and
be like this is gonna be a little
awkward but it's my job to make sure
that
you five people have the best [__]
time right now that's so great and it's
it's [__] hard it's like you man like
diets like that like before I go out on
stage and stuff just like I'm like
nervous I'm more nervous for the small
shows than I am the big ones because I
know that the big ones will go off well
right but the small ones it's like and
like I really don't want to look like a
[__] idiot you know what's crazy I
think it's the same thing with me so no
show where especially for me like if
it's in the hometown I know I got homies
in there of course I'm feeling great
dude yeah like if it's a if it's where
I'm not really super in my element and
there's like not a lot I'm gonna have
like different age people to impress
yeah if I have to do different things
and it's just a mindfuck kind of yeah
but it's so dope that like that that's a
huge thing within your guys's culture I
mean obviously I'm sure not every band
does it but yeah yeah I'd be willing to
bet that a lot of people in you guys's
culture does show out I do notice
there's something we definitely we put
we hold ourselves up to like a higher
standard to try to like at the very
least on practice right yes but we try
to go above me on that and but that's
hard to do you know like being like hey
all [__] five of you [__]
open up this [__] pit even though you
know okay [__] five people this room
jump jump you know like what do you
wanna do you do you we play the [__]
show play it what it is just like we
would any other night we're not gonna do
you like you do you express this to the
people god we just said just send it the
same way we normally would there's even
been times were like our guitar player
Eric like I've been like dude like
because we have like choreographed like
parts in our set and like there was some
nights was like dude like I mean this
crowd doesn't look like a jumpin crowd
this crowd doesn't look like this like
man I'm really nervous like we should
just cut that and like he's thank God
for this man and my [__] life
Eric cuz he goes no [__] that don't be a
[__] go [__] do it and I'm just like
yeah okay
so if my [__] guitar player sell me
like don't be a [__] [__] to go do
you like just do it no I go out and I do
it and it works and it's just like cool
sometimes you just need good [__]
that you're on the edge and you just
need some of the [__] push you off
yeah and you just get out there and do
it
he's gonna walk offstage regret it's
practice exactly shout-out to I've got a
musician's home uni America helps me out
to the Eric's at Eric's panic attacks
all right who else you got in the band
we've got Eric bright
and Brent yeah brightens the drummer and
he's honestly probably like one of the
best drummers in the [__] like
Pacific Northwest he's a dude he's
insanely good and like I always say he's
like my diamond he's my hidden gem cuz
like when I when I found him and started
playing music with them like I was like
dude he's really good like I'm surprised
like no one big as came and like got him
you're like looking around you're like
yeah no for real I was just like wait
he's not really do anything and I know
he wants to do this [__] I was like hey
and he was like yeah so he like started
playing with me and my old band towards
the end but then the dead crowd started
and like yeah it's been all good but
yeah he's he's like he's he's really
[__] good he's one of those people
that's like he's he's a master of his
craft he said sound behind drums and
like not even just metal like he's just
traditionally good at his instrument on
all [__] fronts and can put on a
clinic and how'd you guys get get like
oh my old band we we needed a drummer
and I he was just like this really
[__] good drummer I was like I always
thought that like oh he's really good
he's probably busy and like I hit him up
one day he's like yeah I ain't got [__]
going on we always assumed they fit
right dude yeah and I was just like well
do you want to like go on to her laughs
he's like yeah I'd [__] love to I was
like well here's my band like you want
to come to her he's like yeah yeah and
then like you know shut up already know
our set
I love how cynical like some dudes
conversations can be like boiled down to
be so simple yeah yeah yeah and Eric's
Eric's [__] he's the man - he's
[__] like he has a daughter and [__]
okay and I've never seen someone be it
like most time in music when someone has
a kid it's usually like oh wow well
dreams dead you're not he balances his
his life so well and stuff where he's
able to do everything and he's still
[__] great dad and he's a great
[__] guy
you know Brighton he's oh that's the
other thing like with dead ground like
it's it's the first man I've kind of
been and where everyone we're all best
friends and it's all [__] good people
and like it's because they're all growth
mindset yeah yeah we're whirling
yeah dude and like we everyone can drink
and do drugs and handle their [__]
everybody you know everyone can [__]
hang like there's gonna handle your
vices now
yeah yeah and and we can all hang so
like when we're in social situations
dealing like I was so nearly like when
we showed up and met up like hung out
with the tillow and stuff great like I
don't have to worry about like oh dude
this guy's gonna be [__] weird he's
gonna turn someone off because we're
meeting these people for the first time
and it's like right you're gonna like us
you got these things who you love them
but you like please don't [__] punch
this guy or don't say something really
[__] weird or awkward don't [__]
give them like weird vibes oh my god
I'll make rape jokes on the first day
yeah [__] like that yeah all my guys you
put them in a room with anyone all of
them can chill and hang yeah yeah okay
oh that's not like it like this if like
my dudes had to come hang out with like
a bunch of like rap hip-hop EDM people
it wouldn't be able to tell no doubt
it's great like they're awesome I love
ya I always love mixing with different
times yeah yeah but okay so I guess some
metal people that wouldn't be able to do
that and would just be like you know
likes coffee about it and we just we
[__] party with everyone you know I
mean I think it's just it's not even
about them the band it's just people
yeah there's just some [__] weird
people out there yeah that's the best
way to [__] that's okay wait so do we
have sorry
and then Brit dead crown is yeah yeah
and then there's brandy plays bass and
he's just like she's just one of the
[__] chills dudes ever and he's kind
of like I'm kind of like that the band
dad yeah and life and daddy and he's
like my second-in-command so anything
like I need especially out in the room
yeah I like do when we drove through
like a snowstorm blizzard it was my
first time like putting on chains and
like he was in the back sleeping I was
like Brent mm-hmm it's a blizzard oh you
need to I need to put chains on the
tires I don't know how and he just gets
out of the van [__] it's seven
degrees out we're in a blizzard and he's
like just put some on he's like all
right you're good to go you know just
like anybody hallmark movies dude it is
it really [__] his Bret's just like
always a dude where it's just like hey
dude I'm really [__] stressed out
he's like he's gotten together yeah he's
got it together he's like let's go he's
the rock yeah and then Brian's just like
hi he sleeps her all the bad [__] but no
he's like dude everyone it's cool dude
like our dynamic is um I'm very thankful
and blessed to have this dynamic because
I know a lot of bands do not have this
but everybody in their band is like
their own [__]
dude has their own personality and like
we all shine in our own different way
and it's [__] great it's just it's a
beautiful thing it's a beautiful dynamic
and I'm so blessed like have this
[__] weird little thing that we do
together with each other yeah dude it's
so great that you can have I mean you
can really cover a lot of the areas of
your life I think it like a friendship
you have my time I have something that
I'm doing that's fruitful I have
something that's not just short-term its
long-term what's what you guys is like
so so you just released the album
obviously a lot of momentum what's uh I
mean what's your flirtin with the next
five years like do you guys just gonna
get it keep keep going keep yeah like
that's the other thing like we just the
other week we like so yeah that's the
other thing we write music and Eric's
bedroom like like we're sitting on his
bed like writing I dude it's like the
most like not fancy [__] either like
this room we're in right now like kicks
the [__] out of like where we like make
our records this does yeah yeah yeah we
know we're not in studios or anything
like that we're in our guitar players
bedroom because he's also an audio
engineer so he does all of our [__] so
it's it's tight but um yeah it sounds
good as listen to on Spotify with some
showers morning yeah yeah does he master
it - yep
all Eric yeah do you guys like like any
of you that downplay yourself look at
what like I give you all this in the
house [__] is so crazy I bless with that
- yeah we were able to do so much - in
house so it's like it's a blessing and a
curse because like I wish service times
we're gonna be like let's just pay this
[__] so we don't have to deal
with it course Oh like you know and then
like I remember when we were sending off
masters for this [__] like Eric was he
he was going through some like oh you
cuz like it's our label debut there was
so much pressure and he was like like I
remember we submitted the Masters and he
calls me one morning freaking out and he
was like dude are they is it too late I
want to go back to the old versions like
I want to I want to know we can't you
know doubt and I was like I was like
dude it's already sent off to distro
there's nothing we can do about it he
was just like [__] and I was like dude
it's not that bad just chill out like
even have a sound was it fun yeah it's
what you hear on Spotify yeah but like
for like dude there was those moments
where like he was tripping and like it
made me trip for a second but then I had
to be like dude it's fine do that
because I think it's probably the brain
brain of an engineer I can't let [__] go
like I I'm like yeah like yeah once it's
out I'm like oh I could have done this
better because I'm this but yeah that's
that's part of being that's part of
being an artist and engineer too and
like me and him we're both like that
like he's every music video I see him I
God could have change that could have
done that you know coulda shoulda woulda
but like that's the one thing like you
know I've always been pretty good at is
like not getting hung up on that [__]
and like you know always like there's
some people that just won't push it out
because they're like they're so caught
up and like what they did yesterday yes
and it's just like dude that's so
unhealthy yes putting out something is
always better than putting out nothing
yeah you just need to push it out there
dude we were talking about
you could probably weigh in on this
because you know you know social media
pretty well and you know the dynamics of
clouds and stuff so ha social media
that's a crazy one so so Gary Vee do you
know that is yeah yeah yeah so I listen
to him man he had this perspective I was
listening to a while back about so like
Instagram I'm not having likes right so
they're they're gonna get rid of likes
and say I'm such a [__] dude it's so
the people okay so say you have I had
the same scenario say you have five
songs you they're completely different
genres you're like I like all of them in
and the only one that gets popular is
number four and it's a [__] country
song and you're like God country is
pretty cool but like I love country but
but that one gets popular yeah and so
you have your whole career the next five
years you're just like country music
country music country because that one
was the most popular and the five videos
you posted now you just let the
popularity of that one video decide your
whole career because of the likes on
Instagram and Gary Vee was saying like
this is something you should do no no no
no he was basically pointing out that
like that's a flaw like it's taking all
yes mr. Graham is almost yeah hat like
capturing an artist mind and like you
own is to sell yeah because I whenever
that yeah um before the algorithm really
[__] my [__] up like dude I cuz I got
like eleven thousand followers on
Instagram and I remember like year two
ago I post anything and get [__]
thousands of flags all this [__] and
I'll be like [__] yeah you know feels
good in the head dude if I'm not gonna
[__] lie felt [__] good comments
every dude like I had girls [__]
being like
ha I was like oh that's sick I've never
got caught huh but got caught before
yeah yeah yeah dude it was sick and then
like the algorithm started hitting in
and then that's when I noticed I'm
getting more attention when I post a
selfie then like my music [__] then that
starts [__] with your brain and
actually this last year like when like
that actually [__] me up pretty hard
the whole because now like if I post
something I'm lucky if it brings 100
likes and when you go from you're
getting thousands of likes and
interactions on your [__] down like
nothing like even with the algorithm
stuff you you're conscious you know it's
there but for me it was like and I I
deal with like depression and [__] like
that already so it was like a big like
mind [__] yeah it pull of duty if it
[__] me up pretty hard for a little
bit and I'd like transition it really
really roughly but it was dude yeah it
was [__] man it was weird you're
you're so used to like getting all this
[__] and then like it just stops out of
nowhere and then you're like what's
wrong with me
am I not like do people not like me
anymore why aren't like just a month ago
like I was getting all these lot like
you can't even logically talk yourself
out of cuz like okay it's the algorithm
whatever yes nealy and then it just yeah
it just keeps going down down more on
yours like okay maybe it's knockout
maybe it's me you know like is it really
happening as bad as ever dude what's
silly freaking thoughts wallet dude so
we grab on to those like their ass dude
yeah and then it started happening to
our band page too and then I was like
okay this is that's when I was just like
all right [__] Instagram yeah dude I
have to that's how
yeah it's it's crazy I know it's very
it's it's I can't imagine being a band
starting out right now with that with
Facebook and Instagram ads currents
platforms because like dude it's you are
discouraged from the get-go all those
platforms like it's so tough I so tough
yeah it's it's almost it's you you're
pretty far behind the race if you just
started you know exactly so imagine like
being like or even you like you start a
new music project you're like all new
socials [__] here we go I know I know
like flooded your reach is 5%
go get him did you know I've had this
humbling though it's kind of been nice
because I did I started a new music
project and I
I did it just on my regular social media
yeah and it's it's more of sound arts
really has nothing to do if any of my DJ
stuff it's fine it's very you know lot
of spoken word poetry sort of stuff hell
yeah but it's a like I released it after
not having social media I feel like I
had kicked like the dopamine like likes
and stuff yeah and the first couple ones
I released it and I was able to like I
don't really care about the likes and
stuff that's nice like I'm getting more
likes that's cool but as a guy like I've
learned much my transition was rough but
I learned and now I'm like you got to do
it I think it I think it's something
that a lot of people are gonna have to
like cope with and dude yeah yeah
because there's a lot of people who they
think they're not or they maybe don't
realize it but they're super addicted to
like notifications in life oh yeah it
controls what they do so like oh I'm
where I posted a picture of my blue
eyeshadow or my red eyeshadow and this
one has more like so that's the woman oh
yeah yeah yeah what about deep inside
what about what yeah I want to wear
today what's Fox man it's it's and like
yeah I was never like I've always been
pretty aware of that stuff especially
with like my mental [__] and all the
[__] I have going on I knew that like
that was a slippery slope but you know
just with like my transition with it all
I was aware but it was still hard
nonetheless because like I was this guy
that like I I have people on the
internet that know me for a thing and
then like it was like oh I'm reaching
all of you guys you guys are seeing all
my [__] and you guys are digging it too
like oh nothing like that was hard to
cope with because I already like I had
like this little following yeah and then
it was just like I felt like I was taken
away from me one it's like yeah it's
almost like it's like what like I don't
you almost want to be a little mad at
like Instagram yeah no I was but like
thankfully I was never too attached to
that [__] and like good guy I use social
media because it's like it's my platform
like promote my business and the things
I do and so like now like like running
all the bands whole just this stuff it's
like I have to be on it and I have to do
it but now like I'm on Christmas
vacation I'm just like oh I could put my
[__] phone down and walk away from it
good I love it yes I love it because
yeah like well like the release is out
it's all done and stuff I don't have to
be on my phone it's gonna do whatever it
does weather yeah yeah yeah and like
there's times like oh I'll get gets my
phone I'll be like Oh
I'll be like a whole bunch of people you
know always reply to like fans and stuff
like yeah because we're having those
experiences and that's a good kind of
social media dude that's like that's a
great feedback loop too because it feels
great do you like yeah and it's not like
like we're not putting [__] out there to
like be like oh like all the [__] it's
more just like people are messaging us
like do our [__] Instagram requests
like our album dropped December 6
well technically December 5th our 9:00
p.m. West Coast times when it dropped as
soon as that happened or Instagram
requests just woke up the next morning
and was just scrolling because we had so
much and so it's like our Instagram
folder it's still like I can't go
through all of it because there's so
many does that ever stress you out when
you see that number well with with like
going back to what we were saying
earlier like I feel like so much like I
wanna I wish I can sit down and go
through all of them but I can't
mm-hmm and like that makes me feel like
battle let's put yeah but it's also like
it's so great that like people are like
sharing that [__] and they're stoked
about it like I [__] love it but it's
yeah like I don't feel bad about it but
like that's just like that's a good kind
of social media I guess where it's like
we're not putting [__] out there just
for it to get liked it's like oh I'm on
social media now because I want to like
reply and say thank you to people
yeah I'm finding myself just saying
thank you so much like there's so many
things I think that's great yeah I think
it's important for an artist too because
so something through all my meditation
and yoga and in Buddhism learning and
all this stuff
yeah yeah yeah something I've had to do
is what's called loving-kindness Metta
meditation which is essentially instead
of just thinking about the basis of a
meditation you you think about the
people close to you and you know ya feel
gratitude for them and you're like if
you could give them all that like if you
can give them everything they ever
wanted would you and it's like oh of
course it's just a very like
heartwarming feeling yeah I love for
yourself yeah and those things I found
that I you know they're not just like a
fun little thing to feel nice they're
important for your mental health duty
and I think that responding to Instagram
notifications and reading that and not
just letting be another person the other
number they do this as a person that's a
real human like they like your stuff
exactly and that they like they spent
money on my band and [__] and like so
yeah like that that's what like social
medias been about like the last couple
weeks which is like that's the way I
want to use social right it's been a lot
of me being like you can't all of it
you gotta I gotta watch you know like I
just said like like I I can't go through
all this and once it's there's just so
many like I can't sit down and like it
would take me so long dude you know I I
don't get nearly it's even half as many
as you do or even a quart as many as you
do but even my like people will respond
to me or people with with advice and
stuff and sometimes they'll get backed
up weeks and then sometimes all I kind
of i'll just neglect it or whatever but
yeah people get it an instagram is
harder because like they have a whole
message request thing so you don't see
it right away
yeah Twitter like Twitter like that's
where we're most active so like everyone
who like tweets at us I go check it and
then I'm instantly just like yo thank
you so [__] much like thank you like
that's like the best way to get like
well is there a medal crowd on Twitter
is there dude yeah that's where our that
meme went viral of the music video thing
like a Twitter is a different world did
I [__] love Twitter it's my favorite
I haven't been on I quit the Twitter's
oh I quit the Twitter I said like an old
man alright [__] metalcore for
Millennials over here versus boomer
that's the title of this no but I've
been on Twitter as much but it
definitely is a different it's a barrier
I saw this tweet the other day that was
this this guy made this joke about he's
like I forgot that Twitter isn't real
life he's like oh he said something I
wanted to kill himself or something in
real life and he's like when my
co-workers was with like was like what
bro like this [__] you could say like
all [__] died on Twitter but like in
real life if you say that people like it
was yeah yeah and the other thing with
Twitter yeah like I see a lot of people
and I don't know what your reasons were
for like taking a break from it or
whatever but I see a lot of people who
are like man this this social media
platform it's so [__] toxic it's so
[__] negative it's so this it's like
well yeah it is but also like what I've
done and what I've been pretty conscious
of a I never want to be a guy that gets
on social media and all you see from me
is negativity cuz there's so many
[__] that do that they only get
on the internet to [__] and complain
about [__] I can handle it dude no I
can't either and so guess when I when
I'm if I follow you and I see you doing
that too much guess what I do I go and
[__] unfollow you boom negativity
toxicity go you don't have to see it and
so likes of curating your own feed and
that's like it's like okay if you want
to leave Twitter like go for but also
just so you know like anyone out there
like if you like you could just clean up
your [__] newsfeed please and be like
I encourage you it was there please
encourage I started doing that yeah I've
never felt like I needed to like
absolutely leave a social media platform
because it was like too negative is like
oh well that's that person's making
anger so I'm just gonna unfollow him I
think that the feeling the need to
follow every person you've ever met and
every person that you went to school
with and all the family members do this
is something that if you're okay cool
you're checking it every single day when
you're checking every single day are you
inserting 17 negative thoughts into your
brain throughout the day exactly and
that's what I mean and this is also like
a like don't be that person on social
media right don't be that person like
you only get on the [__] [__] about
something or whenever you reply to
someone every interaction you have on
social media it's something negative
like imagine that cuz I see that from so
many people on the internet it's like
cut it out yeah and I've even responded
to people there's been a couple of
people who have liked message like hit
me back on Twitter and stuff about some
things and for the most time it's like a
troll or negative and I'm I like sit
back and I think I'm like dude I've
never seen you compliment anything I've
never seen you say anything good about
something and I hit him back and I go
hey do you ever say anything positive
like do you only troll on this thing
like do you do you ever say anything
good on this and then most time they
never say [__] and then they stop you
know it's crazy then I just call it a
nice I ain't calling them out is
actually like yeah it's not in a dick
way there's just like hey do you ever
say anything positive on here well
sometimes you gotta like people out of
there yeah oh yeah you're right like if
I followed me like yeah I would just see
negative [__] all the time did we get
confused with all these likes and these
pictures and all these little things
it's like these are humans yeah and
we're saying yeah I need to watch you
watch your mouth yeah again it's also
bad too because there's been times where
like I used to I would get big pops I
probably would too if I went on Twitter
and I bitched about something really
hard I would get such a [__] huge pop
because people love that [__] they eat
it up too and they would be like yeah
[__] that [__] this you know and then
some person well you know try to argue
but dude like there's been times like
I've noticed it too I'm like dude
whenever I say some negative on Twitter
like
kind of pops off and does pretty well
mm-hmm look at media man yeah I do yeah
exactly well thankfully I'm in a spot
now we're like I say positive things and
it pops off on Twitter it says so it's
like yeah making that shift that it
making that shift okay so so I mean
you're positive dude but obviously to
dive into the lyrics obviously the
lyrics are dark
you've obviously someone's dog yeah so
do you ever have times where have you
mentioned the word depression a couple
times you have times where you you mind
too far you're at the bar you can't turn
it on I'm actually a [__] that up I
waited till after this album I have an
appointment tomorrow to go get on meds
finally hell yeah it's been like yeah
I've struggled I got diagnosed when I
was like 15 I showed symptoms of mania
so I can't say I'm bipolar but I feel
bipolar sometimes but I'm definitely not
yeah yeah what I try to say to people is
like I don't have good days I have good
stretches in good weeks okay so like
I'll have a week in times where I'll
like I'll wake up super early I'll be
like [__] yes like I'm going [__] and
nothing can stop me and then like dude
just like a week later I I can't wake up
I can't get out of bed
I can't like I just feel it's like oh
man there's like I I just don't feel
consistency with myself and that's been
very [__] exhausting and so that's
why I'm finally going to get meds I used
to be scared of the idea of meds and I
shut that off for a long time when I was
younger I was scared a lot to do yeah
when I was I had the option when I was
younger and I was like no I don't want
it and I was I was scared cuz like my
eggs this is so [__] like especially
that I'm get I'm getting older and I'm
like accepting a lot of these things but
for years I I thought that like my my
depression my anxiety was like my
superpower
what yeah what do you mean because I
would be so anxious all the [__] time
that it would I felt like if I wasn't
that way I wouldn't be on top of my [__]
because I used it to like I would be so
I'd be freaking out all the time about
[__] or I'd be so [__] depressed or
like so I'd be like okay why what I need
to like go take care of these things are
but you're aware and you feel like
you're actually handling
right yeah but but then but then that
create what that created was just like
so much inconsistency where I'm just
like due to emotionally drained from
just myself all the [__] time so now
now that I'm getting older and like I've
been through this for so many years like
you know like we have a song called 24
and it's like and in it's about like you
know kind of people voltaren off me and
like sucking life out of me and [__] but
like you know like taking [__] that's
like kind of mine but also it's like you
know the first line is like 24 and I'm
jaded I'm burnt out and I'm weak it was
also a sign of my mental health it's
like I'm too young to feel this tired
like if I kicked it out before I you
know like I shouldn't feel like that um
yeah
24 much more life there's so much more
and I'm already [__] like most times
I feel over it oh my dude I can get hit
by a [__] car well the fact that you
notice that you don't want to be feeling
that though yeah thing because we love
getting stuck in our [__] we laugh like
yeah this is Who I am
I like hate myself do ya ya know and
like and so yeah I finally was just like
after this record cycle which is done
now and I finally got my appointment I
wanted to wait till the record was out
and stuff too cuz I didn't know I was
gonna [__] with my brain and I didn't
want to go I don't want to go out with
my dues and be like hey by the way I'm
starting to are antidepressants of [__]
like I don't want to [__] with my blog
my brain that's good - I feel like you
know finally going in tomorrow to get
that and my biggest thing with that my
decision was like I just want to feel
consistent and I talked to my mom and
like she she's on meds and stuff too so
like runs in the family and stuff and I
asked her I was like well am I gonna
like lose my edge you know am I gonna
lose my [__] like superpower that's
what I call it it's my super right right
so [__] up cuz it's not my superpower
you know well like that's you know
what's crazy but but my mom was like no
you won't because my mom my mom's a
go-getter she's a [__] hustler just
like me she's like she [__] kills it
she makes like six figures at Kaiser she
started out as a pharmacist tech no
college experience and is [__] like
run and [__] at [__] like modulation
no epic my mom's my [__] superhero
she's [__] awesome so yes she was
like no you won't lose your edge 'trust
cool and I was like okay it's cool
you're able to have that conversation
with it is it is very good in something
that I always try to tell people to
because I've done the antidepressant
reality it's not forever like like if
it's just you know maybe it's a couple
years maybe it's ten years maybe I don't
know and you don't know you don't have
to know exactly just I think the
emphasis on going in and taking the pill
and doing it is that I want so much yeah
try it different ones at work trying to
hook me almost 10 years to come to terms
with like maybe I should get on
medication right because for in it's
been 10 years of just constant battling
with myself and I'm finally at the point
hours just like the battle yeah I'm just
like dude I could just take a pill and
like it could be way easier they can
help but the only way I'll know is if I
do it's all right finally gotten
implants to do that and I'm looking
forward to seeing how things go with
that yeah I think a lot of what I'm
learning on this podcast is the amount
of people who are you know it's great
people are so like willing to be
vulnerable and we're talking about these
things now yeah yeah so many people who
are just cool awesome normal ass people
yeah like hey man I kind of I go through
[__] too and like it's okay to go get
medication and I want to make it normal
to go in and talk to somebody
yeah and it should be thanks for
expressing that oh well do yeah - and
like I mean yeah it's just it's it's
weird I think it's not I'm trying I'm
trying to find my words but like yeah
dude like it it it's a lot a lot of I
just exhaustion that's the only way I
can put it it's just like I'm exhausted
I'm tired of being tired and it's like
man it's it's just yeah it's been a long
long road but it's only been like not
even 10 years but it feels like it's
been a lifetime and it shouldn't feel
that way you said you've been fighting
with the just the idea of like 15 yeah
throughout every day or maybe even like
once a week probably at the very least
like that thought of like should I go
dude that's a thought that you could
have been had thinking about other other
things that's a decision I only have so
many decisions every day it's it's
providing you fog man and you're going
to release it now so that's gram how are
you doing with everything I seen you
like you know you it's been a while
since we've talked but I volume on all
the media's and stuff and like it's like
damn Jake's [__] getting and on some
[__] I'm going hard what's what's so
what are you doing man what's your blood
is because you're you're diving in like
deep with [__] I'm just
holy [__] know what that is like
well alright so essentially for me it's
been like I've been following my DJ path
in my music half but I've also always I
loved like the modal motivational
speaker the authorship the the words of
the poetry like there's so many things
that I'm in drew into and in a lot of it
is like it's like exploring the depth of
it is like humanity and in in philosophy
and psychology like I just I love
culture and I mean I don't know how to
like round it about anthropology just
all these things yeah it has fascinate
me um and just with all my healing
process I've like I've learned all these
things like all these things about
myself about other people that I just
want to I want to share with people so
yeah started getting better I started
like you know healing my own depression
I was very depressed for like six years
but my thing was I was just I locked it
inside I didn't tell anybody like yeah
really I was I was like just especially
suicidal and yeah and I've been there to
like I'm glad the suit it's been a while
since I've had the suicidal thoughts but
I definitely had them and it's not fun
now it's more just like if I was walking
down the road and like a car hit me and
killed me like that's my ticket out
[__] yeah like I'll take it you know
yeah like thoughts like that now not
numbness yeah I just like just like dude
if that did happen like I wouldn't be
mad right you know or if I got you know
terminally sick and died in a week like
hey that's my that's my punch card this
is accepting that's my yep just ha
[__] it's time to go which that's not
good either but ya know I've definitely
been there like that it [__] yeah
apparently we're not supposed to feel
that way yeah for me I have this like
burning does that like I would feel this
but I would always have this other voice
of like like you could you could do
whatever you want like I always have
this like I have these cool ideas and I
have these really cool you know people
tell me my ideas are cool and then I'll
be mumbling about some [__] and going on
and on I look around there's ten people
staring at me listening to every word
I'm saying and I'm like oh [__] you guys
think I'm important
you know like so I I have these moments
and I used to just get so nervous and I
remember I would have out
people when I was younger like teachers
and stuff yeah I didn't like I said I
did have my family time I mean they
believed me but I had a couple teachers
and they pull me the side like Jake your
leaders you do really bad in school too
no I did really good in school I was
really bad and my teachers all the time
being like there's so much potential in
you but well mine was I was weird
III always say that I got lucky I don't
know how it happened or why it happened
I don't know if it's just like I just I
meant it to be a positive dude but yeah
I had every potential to be a [__] like
I have I've been I've been essentially
raising myself since I was around nine
it's kind of how it is night well I was
living on my own I was 15 but really I
didn't know about I didn't I don't know
what your home life was I didn't know
you so actually I have edited I haven't
yet but I had with you until I did at ok
it was essentially I tried to record the
[__] thing to where I'm like who's
Jake runs and what does junkyard love
yeah and I just i rambled for 10 minutes
and just kind of cried a little bit and
said well damn and so I had Shaylee
interview me that's ok a little more
crying but yeah we talked about more
structure attic child they have I just
the thing is is is I really want on the
sprockets I want to set the stage for
people to be vulnerable and be their
true selves and yeah yeah because I feel
I'm trying to explain I know it's final
words I want to I want to walk around as
a portal yes you and I can say I know
what you're saying and I'm just gonna
say this is a perfect place for it
because this is I've done quite a bit of
podcast and I definitely like I feel so
[__] comfortable here
good most comfortable I've probably felt
on a podcast so cool this is great and
you have a very great [__] window and
platform to do that alright and you're
very good at this so yeah thank you I
appreciate tell me that yeah it's
something that I I want to be able to
create this I want to be like create
that because I think that I see people
you know I feel like you know I maybe I
maybe it's a gift if you want to call it
it is see the real people I really like
you know if they're if they can be
bullshitting to me and I'm just like
you're not saying what you're really
saying do yeah yeah yeah yeah
and I feel like I have you know an
innate ability that I can sharp and
that's that's why that's why I hate you
up to come do this cuz yeah and I was
like I want to talk to Jake like this
because I know me and him like it's no
[__] like we can actually be real to
each other like this will be fond yeah
even if this wasn't recorded this would
still be a [__] blast ya know even
catch up a crazy thing like I said I
feel like I'm just like I found this
little life hack where I'm like hey do
you want to learn about [__] do you want
to seek novelty do you want to catch up
with your friends do you want to have a
beer please talk to your friends yeah
yes but cheers Cheers it it's it's it's
good man I'm mining the world for
knowledge and I hope that I'm not
sparking inspiration and creativity and
everybody yeah [__] yeah I want to do
that so this is great yeah it's
wonderful man the life of an artist it's
a crazy life dude and it's definitely um
it's not you do you gotta have a [__]
spot to [__] do this art ship and
like it's definitely not for everyone
and if it was and everyone would [__]
do it especially if you're trying to
make money and [__] like like I said
there I think the biggest quote I have
mine on this ba guy's gotta eat [__] and
learn to love it not just eat [__] but
you gotta learn how to gotta learn how
to love eating [__] that's that's I
think the most important thing you could
do is eat [__] though I think dude it's
we have this like you need to but what
would I get a lot okay something about
guitar yeah like if I'm like hey you
want to play guitar if someone who
doesn't like try they put I stuck a
guitar I can't play it and they would
put their hands up yeah it's like you
you can eat [__] if you want to play
guitar if you're not gonna pick it up
again and be all good brilliant genius
yeah and since you're not a douchebag
you probably well here here's a chord I
put your fingers here yeah see this is
how you start well and here's the thing
is once you meet a bunch of musicians
and DJs and all these people you start
to realize that they're like divid I
want to show you like you want you want
to learn the language that I that I
communicate my emotions in okay yeah
I'll teach you did yeah well yeah yeah
so I think I think you could probably
concur with that any musician yeah like
you can hit them up and they'd they'd
probably be happy to show you a few
things dude yeah yeah and there was even
was like graphic design stuff like that
that's it's not as like open book
because there's like some there's some
[__] out there that are you know
sticklers with their tray but when I was
first starting out there were a couple
designers who like they're still like
doing they do [__] creation one of
them works for Rise Records names
Allen Ashcraft and he does great [__]
work for like really big bands and when
I was first starting out and I was
really shitty he was one of the guys
that like I would hit him up and he
would always message me back and he was
really [__] cool and in the sense of
like I was young didn't know [__] about
it didn't know [__] about the business
that's the other thing once you learned
the craft that's one thing but then you
got to learn the business oh man and
that's was levels to this [__] oh and
that's like that's a whole other
ballpark and that's a whole other
[__] just you're gonna yeah you're
gonna get I got [__] thumped yeah all
the fun stuff you're like alright take
everything that you thought was fun and
then make it yeah and then yeah like but
yeah he was always really cool to me and
I remember him saying like yeah when I
started out in this [__] I had people do
this for me so I'm trying to pass that
back and I'm like [__] yeah that's
really cool and but then at the same
time I had other people who you know
would slam me for certain things online
publicly and be like you know design
snobs you know instead of it where I get
the same exactly yeah every art world
has it you know but um thank God for
people like that like Alan I'm pretty
sure you have people out there too that
you know so much you looked up to and
you were like I'm just gonna send a
[__] message and like they helped you
and they're like yeah you don't go you
know they gave you advice and like
that's cool if there needs to be there
are people out there but I just wish
there's a little more well and I think
even outside of like messaging someone
having them reply yeah I always talk
about like the hero that you walk around
as like you're always wearing a cape
like there's always whoever the [__] you
are you're somebody's Idol there's so
many looking up to you yeah like
whatever you're doing at all times I
remember I saw you're talking about you
guys go ham for five people like it's
you going in so the kids MacLeod if
they're in a van they're like I saw this
pan and they went in for us that's what
I'm gonna do I remember I saw John Bell
Ian at Peter's room downstairs of
Roseland oh yeah that's cool and I love
it down there but it was like first time
I saw him I was like obsessed with him
like recently a couple weeks listening
to him I was like oh he's in Portland so
when it sounds like a hundred people or
something and then I've seen him
probably nine times since then I just
saw him in London a couple months ago
with Shelley London yeah bro we are not
so we got blacked out and just like
we're in the very back like with no
seats which is really
we were just spinning with our fists out
we're so hammered just having fun but
anyway but so so we went from dude he's
selling out arenas and chin toying with
with AJR and all these fans I'm like
he's just this humble dude he I remember
a hundred people on stage he's with his
college bandmates and he's just or
hundred people yeah
under people in crowd and he's just he's
just like thank you guys so much he
plays his heart out he's sweating to
death and he's damn near in tears
through his lyrics yeah and then you see
him at Key Arena you know and he's the
same thing but yeah and that's that's
where like you know like we were talking
like the little pump to overnight
successes they don't have that right
they don't you know like like there's no
bonus yeah like Macklemore you know I
remember he would play Hoffman Theatre
in front of 40 people and then he ended
up you know now he's in [__] motor
center and [__] like dude you I feel
like as an artist like if you are if you
are gonna make it you are gonna break
you are gonna be [__] famous you need
those experiences of like the bottom so
like know where you came from
because if you don't have that then like
dad I feel like that's just really bad
for your your mental state and don't get
famous before you're ready [__] dude
yeah and there's a lot of that sadly
yeah you know yeah I mean I get it
though it's it's one of those things
that I will say though I'm absolutely
yeah who would say no to [__] what
but there's also people above that
should know better and should put their
[__] neck outs for these kids and
should be like hey you like you need to
[__] take care of yourself because
it's not easy yes and you're gonna [__]
yourself up like you know the like
instead they're just they're just taking
their money and being like all right
yeah Ian if you laters in the internet
that you know like dude like if you work
for a union and you get [__] strung
out on drugs or something they have to
pay for your rehab
yeah they if you're a musician you get
strung out on drugs yeah your label can
just ditch you they tell you that yeah
they tell you to get your [__] together
that's the perspective of it they don't
have to do [__] for you and they don't
want to do [__] there's plenty of labels
there's plenty of like other homies
there's point dude there's there's so
many opportunities to be respected and I
think you know if you we do live in a
world of Instagram and tic-tock and all
these like overnight Fame that might
happen so it listener if you happen to
be a young person and you're kind of
experiencing some uptick or you have or
you know somebody who is like just be
smart about this just be smart yeah be
smart that's the biggest thing and like
don't like I said like that I feel like
there's a huge detachment of reality
when it comes to those people that get
way too big way too quick just
always be in reality if you feel like
you're getting out it's okay to take a
step back and come back down
go back to your [__] hometown and
have a beer with your [__] your your
your local [__] mill workers you know
go get you know just take a step back go
back to where you you know go back and
be like this is where I [__] came
from and that's okay to do and then be
like yeah I do have this crazy [__] man
I'm [__] grateful for that it's good
everyone needs to be able to do that
because if you're always submerged and
just yeah I don't even know what I'm
going up you know I know what you're
talking about
I talk about the maze on here often
sometimes we I like to see I think that
the way I naturally see things is sort
of like a lot of times people are in
their maze of whatever their [__] is and
I'm like looking up at the maze a lot of
times we're so into our maze and we're
fighting all of our individual like get
the [__] back the Democrats get the [__]
back Republicans get the [__] back
country artists or whatever it is but
but you you forget that you're in a maze
and it's just like oh yeah that's my
remember your yeah yes individual thing
like all that like that Fame and all
that [__] it's it's reality but it's
only reality to a certain extent dan of
the day you still need loved ones to
come home to like real loved ones and
that's a thing a lot of these kids like
these little palms like you don't just
[__] porn stars who are just like I'm
just [__] you because you're the
flavor of the week Jesus do they not
understand that they don't understand
that like dude like and that's what
would [__] with your mind is just like
dude like you're like [__] you is
just clout right hanging out with you is
clout for me I'm not hanging out exactly
like dude just imagine being surrounded
by that all the time and thinking that
it's real you know honestly it makes me
like so it likes just sad honestly it's
sad it's really sad because dude when I
was 14 if you gave me everything I ever
wanted I would have loved to have it
forever
[__] yeah you don't know dude it's a
thing no no when you're two years old
you want a binky or whatever but it
could also go back to you know that dude
at that [__] Ford dealership that I
met and grass ain't always greener man
yeah you know like it's the same thing
you could be there but it's like dude
you're just because it seems all good
doesn't mean it is and yeah the other
day we're all human and everyone's got
their [__] but I just I just with but
especially the music and arts I just I
really hope that they kind of do
something for these young people that
get really famous and really rich quick
and they almost like a union or like
[__] a non-profit
like their neck in and help them be like
also just like hey you have a lot of
money now let's get you a [__] house
let's get you invested in financial
advisors yeah and then someone that's
not financially advising for them you
know it's like nonprofit and someone
that's like well let's just get you
counseling let's get you things like
keep your head [__] straight yeah
listen to their lyrics what are they
saying what did they maybe need and
that's there's what I say about him all
time I guarantee if he was singing about
his [__] mom and dad's divorce more
and not about baby baby this and having
a girlfriend when he was 15 years old
probably wouldn't have been such a big
douche bag oh well that's goes back to
the thing about the like so they're like
hey sure game to him and he's like hey
you know what's gonna sell is you saying
baby baby yeah singing about little
[__] 13 year old girls and being
there possible like no that's not
[__] real bit that's definitely his
path and I don't know like I mean that's
probably an important path yeah yeah
yeah and like he figured himself out and
[__] but like do just imagine if like
you know that little kid was like hey
like your parents did get divorced I
really did [__] with your head do you
want to talk about it right dude you
know what even just that sentence crazy
and going through all these like for me
no because it says yeah a lot of people
yeah yeah and like and you know that
like that really wasn't his option it
was like here's a song [__] here's
the lyrics [__] sing it well [__]
yeah if I could go we're gonna make you
your [__] power machine now there's
so many [__] hands in the pot you got
to make us money [__] go you know it's
weird the music industry is so weird
it's not all weird though that there is
a lot of you know like BAM camp and all
these other oh well yeah even like the
record label we're on like they're
[__] awesome I love my team like yeah
and like what you guys is like creative
control in your oh dude so [__] yes
they sick recording shout out to France
from Attila he's the guy that owns it
Mike Milford he's the guy that basically
like runs the whole label and I've
wanted to work with him since I was like
15 he put out like some of my favorite
and now you're working with it yeah he
put out some my favorite medical records
when I was a kid and then to have that
guy hit you up me like you trying to
start on a [__] deal or what meet up
with one you know it's been like such a
cool thing but and then a Billy and John
over at the label as well basically like
because we put out an album on our own
and we did pretty well with it and so
and we had this like creative freedom to
do whatever we want so when we got the
offer essentially and we met up for
lunch we were just like hey we want to
make sure we have all this and he's like
yeah like we're a new label and we're
trying to do things in new ways
see out go for it no [__] no
[__] yeah and like dude the
percentages are very fair like we get 25
percent after expenses are recouped
which people are like only 25 percent
inter standards like eight to ten so
yeah that's pretty [__] good they
don't touch our publishing which is
[__] amazing like dude it was the
most cutting most contracts I've seen
contracts are like what's your touring
what's the no so that's just a label
side but Mike the dude who runs the
label he also manages like Attila and
Chelsea grin so he's like a huge band
manager and he's he doesn't have to do
any of that [__] for us but he kind of
is like talented all you [__]
are like yeah yeah but it's so like he
helps us with a lot of [__] that he
doesn't have to help us out with yeah
cuz when you sign with a record label
it's like no they're not in charge of
your touring that's like diets your
booking agent your manager that's like a
whole other spectrum of the business so
um but yeah he helps us out with [__] he
helps facilitate stuff for us but yeah
dude like the creative control working
with them just basically been like we
want to do this and instead of them
being like you're doing [__] our way
they're like the kind of label at least
in our experience that are like they're
like we like what you guys are doing we
signed you for that reason so we are
behind you and let us help you so it's
been like dude much love for stasek
recordings they're [__] awesome and
I'm glad that like we signed with them
and we're working with them because I
know it's different at other places
right so okay so when you guys when you
guys planning towards you do a lot of
touring I feel like something that's
super dope about your kind of music is
when you're writing it and when you're
practicing it it's it's a lot more like
you're planning that for the live show
like this is gonna go hard live this
part is what we need live this is this
is where the double kick is and that's
what's gonna make this happen right so
venues like you've you've gone through a
lot of venues now I want to talk about
venues like so so I haven't done a crazy
ton but I haven't done some I have like
old buildings in an old structure in
like novelty in originality and
buildings and stuff I'm fat dude I love
it like do like our Columbia Theatre in
Longview so beautifully so yeah you know
so I don't know I guess let's just flirt
with venues
Kevi what's your bene experience you
guys have played sooo many different
ones okay for sure yes so like that's
that's kind of like the blessing and the
curse with like this world of music I'm
in we've played really [__] cool
venues and then we played some like oh
like I'm holes in the wood I wouldn't
wish any my friends to play these ladies
like dive bars or I'll do worse than
that so like a perfect example like this
last where we just did you know we
started out at Hawthorne Theatre excuse
me and then went to El Corazon which
like those are like traditional historic
like music venues you know like in the
sense that like they're old buildings
they're not like the nicest places in
the world but venue wise they're set up
perfectly like they got green rooms they
got all this [__] and they just got rich
[__] history you know it's like
everyone who's someone has been to these
places and played you know it's sick and
then like tonight for that we went to
Boise we played this venue that was like
walked in and I was like whole this was
way like almost over-the-top like a huge
[__] room way bigger than like we
should have been in like they had like
pro [__] like lighting [__] they had
like all this stuff it was a brand new
building almost like it was super sick
don't get me wrong but like it was a
newer place really [__] nice so it
was like still kind of weird in that
sense and then like we went to Salt Lake
City Utah and played in a garage that
was converted into a venue that didn't
have any heat and it was like 30 degrees
it's good for guitar players fingers
dude yeah and like just like the
smallest little [__] hole in the wall
like you know I'm not gonna say the
venue name but like people weren't very
competent at their jobs there but it's
like wait we're in a garage so yeah like
I don't [__] blame you oh yeah the
bar is lower look I do the bar so low
yeah so like there's been like dude it's
every two or it like it fluctuates so
much we've played places that like it's
like one night we're like at this like
huge [__] theater like place that
like you know [__] 36 crazy fish just
played or some [__] or like [__] yeah
oh like some band that you're just like
oh [__] they were just here last
and then like the next day you're like
in this [__] like like goddamn I've
played at the back room of a skate shop
that was like no bigger than this garage
that also had a halfpipe in it so we had
to play on the halfpipe that kind of
sounds tight uh that's the thing
sometimes those small shows like those
were like dude like literally we played
venues that are smaller than this room
we're in right now dude yeah and
sometimes it's really sick and sometimes
it's really not sick it's sick when like
cuz like when it's this small you could
put 20 people in here and would feel
[__] packed and it's sick and you can
get some mad energy in there oh man so I
before I redid this room before I made
it a studio when it was more of just
kind of like I was down is like a man
cave like I should throw parties down
here [__] yeah I had a couple of me in
my close homies we did it was like 20
people and we did like more of a
sentimental vibe that's sick I I wrapped
a little bit [__] yeah I challenged -
yeah yeah so you can catch the vibe when
it's a small room but it is an award
when it's like it's such a small room
that people are just like it's like
they're regular like there's a regular
at the bar yeah and they're like they
hate that you're [__] there you ever
have that no because thank God ball dude
so that's the kind of good thing but
kind of bad thing like because it's
metal music like you can't just go to
any dive bar and be like let's book a
show you're like oh that's true it is
selective it's very selective so like
there's like bars are like no you can't
[__] play your metal music here like
like no [__] Sandra and [__] Kathy
who are teachers at the school and are
coming for their [__] afternoon rows
I do not want to [__] hear your
breakdown because they have to wake up
tomorrow morning and send a postcard to
Carol exactly exactly yes so like that's
a cool thing whenever we are playing
these venues it's harder to find them
but like thankfully we're at the point
where like we you know we usually don't
have to book our tours anymore and like
it's we're kind of established so we
don't have to worry about finding place
guys like the time is yeah yeah
but yeah it's like the places we play
it's mainly like oh you're gonna get
some kind of alternative music scene
through here and that's what it's made
for so that's cool yeah yeah that
definitely comes with like the yeah this
is definitely very alternative
this is there's not a whole lot of money
coming in this place this thing I feel
like music has venues have different
vibes the guy at different venues I mean
I I do more for my audio engineering I
do more like corporate gigs yeah and so
it's not as intricate you know there's
not as many like details to like like
what's that sharpie say down there in
the corner you know but but there I like
finding myself like you know I'm not
supposed to be in the service hallway so
let's check that out or I'm up here in
the bleachers while people are setting
up down here and like just intricate
things so I'm sure that you've you've
explored videos in different ways so so
green rooms for any listener there's no
green room is for the artist to prepare
in and before right all right yeah do
your drugs drink in the show yeah hang
out get the hookers in there yeah I
usually do like a little bit like power
yoga before the set or something like
that do you really yeah like DDP yoga I
did that program for like six months
straight
no [__] way I cannot wait I'm gonna
make you talk about this for an hour
okay I I'm a [__] though and sadly like
I fell off the wagon but me doing it
that long I actually learned so much
from yeah because I did it almost every
day for six months straight
and like dude I felt the best I've ever
felt in my life but I'm just I don't
know what happened I just haven't done
it inside you never failed I mean yeah I
know that's like my little brother like
he wrestles and stuff and last night he
was like my blower back my hips hurt and
I was like well I know why that is come
here and like I was able to like do some
yoga [__] with him and he was like yeah
like I feel way looser and I was like
yeah and like there was some [__] that
like I was doing no problem just from
like the little time I had with yoga
that he was like dude like like the
natural just like heels on the ground
squatting down completely right a lot of
people can't do that yeah and like is it
was like like he was like you had this
hurt so I was like yeah because your
hips are like clothes like dude you need
to like you need to open that [__] up
and yeah I let him touch it it's magical
dude exactly your hips theirs theirs
dude I think it's there's the key to
everything your hips tan is downright
mystical man yes man and yeah it's also
power yoga too so like it's it works on
like you know gets a like I'll get a
pump in
I'll get a stretch I'll get a pump so
like I feel loose but also like I just
did a bunch okay okay so DDP yoga has
Diamond Dallas Page yes and yes was like
combined with calisthenics right and
disco therapy is is just like it's a its
power yoga essentially dude I can't wait
to try it I feel like I want to try it I
I my girl Adrian just yoga with Adriene
on on YouTube
I would never tour anything in my whole
life another would I just yeah I feel
yeah no I'm just kidding I don't really
care he's I've never torn to didn't
think my life actually no when I was 16
I tortured Ableton because I had
somebody else we've never torn tit a CD
or an album or anything either yeah
cease and desist yeah thankfully we have
streaming companies that just do that
for us now and we just pay them nine
bucks a month excessive amounts of just
of just heroin in your butt oh yeah yep
yeah exactly yeah but um yeah like you'd
like dude every venue does have its own
vibe and that's what I mean like you
know we went from like Hawthorne in El
Corazon which are like your typical
famous [__] rock-and-roll venues the
vibe you walk in you're like yep we're
definitely playing a [__] like
rock-and-roll metal show tonight feel it
you can feel it yeah and there's so much
history there and then that's what I
mean like we went to this other venue in
Boise that was like it was really nice
but was like too nice and it was just
like this is sick and everything but you
had the vibes off it's like I feel like
I'm walking through like a like like
like real estate people should be
working in this building you know let me
break a glass yes
yeah can we throw some [__] shitty
stickers on the wall can we make it
smell like cigarettes yeah yeah no but
they like don't get me wrong the venue's
super-sick the people that work there
were probably some of the best people
that we've like ran into because that's
the thing with these traditional like
rock n roll metal then who's like
everyone that works there I think it's
like a rule that you have to be like
jaded and just like a [__] [__] to
everyone when you go to El Corazon I'm
like yeah I know all these people
they're gonna be kind of [__] it's
just how they are it's all good they
could turn out to be like those people
that once you get to know them it's
like man I'm seeing your stupid yeah
I've seen you I've seen you for five
years you're an [__] what's up Steve
yeah and like that's kind of how it is
at the el corazon like yeah like dude
but it's that there's just it's sort of
explained just the rich history of like
an authentic venue and yeah all those
guys have been dealing with [__] punk
ass little punk rock right that'll be
hard man yeah they're hard as [__] and
but yeah so like let's go to the
Millennium and then you be able to like
this other venue where it's like it's a
coffee shop in front than this like huge
it's like it feels like a modern updated
like mega church like like as far as
like the look in the vibe like know
exactly the feeling yeah yeah like like
when you walk in I could say [__] I can
do all this stuff no one's like being
like you can't swear anything
but like the look of it in the feel like
the room it's like if a church was like
oh we need to like the electric beam
right right like that yeah okay do you
ever since it's modern it's like you
know you know as the musician on stage
especially the lead man it's your you
are in control of the vibe I mean five
is such an important word but do you
ever feel like you have to do a little
more in those rooms like like reset it
yourselfers or like yeah either do more
or do less or change it and that's the
thing it's kind of like change what you
do or change yeah yeah yeah and like not
drastically cuz like I mean or we got
our [__] down to like kind of like we we
we have our blueprint also we're the
kind of band we're like we press
spacebar on our MacBook and I we're on
the grid with everything well because
you prepared well yeah and like and we
like we back track our second guitar
through an actual rig that's when
there's four of us not five of us and
then like we have back tracks to go
through the house so our drummer needs
to be on a metronome '''l do you love to
brainstorm later actually about how you
do all this oh I get interesting clinic
I haven't worked with a ton of bands ya
know it's sick I love our library so
don't but yeah so like we so but with
the way we did we have like interludes
before all the songs but yeah we hit
spacebar and like our whole set goes and
we know everything that's gonna happen
and like I even down to like the things
I need to talk about the things I need
to push and all that stuff and so it's
like sometimes there's nights where it's
like just like you know if it's like a
small
it's like it like for example like our
Seattle and Portland shows is like big
dick rooms big dick vibes
people are [__] there to see us I can
be the [__] man I don't have to be so
intimate I don't have to I can say order
the [__] I want and just use hype
[__] phrases of speech and then like
when this shows get smaller and stuff
that's when I could you know I'm like I
can't go up and just be big dick all the
time you know if you feel weird so I'm
that's when I change it up and I'm just
a little more intimate I'm a little more
myself a little more you have to put on
this you know it's it's a mask for sure
but when you're aware of it and you kind
of been controlled and and I know when
to turn it on and what not to right but
the big shows like that yeah it's it's
part of the show like when it's those
big ones but when it's like I'm in a
roomful like new people and stuff and
like I'm not gonna go out and just be
like I'm not like it feels wrong going
up and being like yo [__] do some like
that's like me in tomorrow's like Jesus
yeah but I got with Kathy and dude yeah
yeah and like like I still do that to an
extent but like not as like hardcore as
if like you know it's different when the
whole rooms are to see you you know and
I've experienced that to men like I said
I I broke the whole rooms there to see
you dude you can say where the [__] you
want and you've got no type dude yes but
it's something that you have to keep
control of exactly yeah you gotta wear a
different mask in it yeah different so
like so like just that's what I mean
like the changes I have to make and like
the vibe and stuff it's like obviously I
read the [__] room that's part of
being a frontman if you don't read the
room in your frontman you need to
[__] do that because you're probably
making a [__] fool out of your so you
want a little detail on on reading the
room this is something just because I'm
a DJ so I can kind of yeah you know you
have to read the when you're reading the
room what's your do you read the room
before so like after soundcheck and
you're like okay we've got [__] 30
minutes hour or whatever it is like do
you start watching the people who walk
in do you sneak from backstage you what
what's your oh yeah watch it I'll keep
my eyes open and yeah for sure yeah I'm
kind of like I have eyes this last tour
I tried to not do that so much because I
was kind of getting in my head with some
[__] and I was like no like dude you
just need to go out and put put on the
show you need to put on
like you you know and I would find
myself just thinking too hard about
things so I tried to not do that so much
but yeah I'm deaf definitely like yeah
I'm going out and I'm seeing if there's
people there I'll ask for motors like
how do you think tonight's gonna go
that's right do you think there's gonna
be some kids here you're always like
yeah it's not like a few people I always
downplay ourselves I'm just like well
not downplay I'm just like yeah I mean
it should be fun night that's why I say
should be fun hey there you go it's
gonna be a fun night regardless dude
your minds always listen and I always
think that like dude like [__] even if
you're bullshitting yourself like you're
at least listening it's a [__] take
that placebo from yourself yeah yeah I
guess I don't downplay but I try to like
I try to not be the guy that's like yeah
we draw pretty [__] big and then like
no one shows up it's like especially
when you're talking to a promoter and
you're trying to be like you know how's
it looking tonight you know it's just
like the best thing to say is just like
well regardless we're not fun tonight
yeah it's always the best way to go we
are dude at the end of the day that's
all you're really trying to do it is
like look what you're doing like you got
a you know you're trying all these
things you're you're touring you're
making all this music but what you're
like what's what you can really be
looking at what you're doing is you're
playing some music that you love with
your friends yeah and it's an alive
curator well that's what I was talking
about actually so when I was talking
about kind of like a portal I want to be
a portal to people being them their
truest self their real vibe curator yeah
well well that's that's you know the
thing with these venues you felt that
you walk in you're like oh Lord oh this
people come here The Lion the Witch and
the Wardrobe man that they had this you
know you go into the wardrobe and it
yeah it takes you to somewhere else but
but I think that certain people certain
events certain things and in places
happen intuitively that to elaborate on
that to yet there are certain venues
like where with all of us in the band
it's like like yeah that that's showin
Idaho that venue though like you know
felt like Mike
like a modern youth group Church you
know right that was like hip and cool
but like it wasn't that by any means but
like yeah we were all just like
you know like those shows we all walk
offs Asian were like we don't know how
we did you know cuz it's like it's so
different
yeah and then it's like it's like yeah I
don't know and then it's like oh well we
sold a [__] ton of merchandise so
obviously people liked it you know so
it's like yeah but it just felt weird
felt different but whatever there's such
a learning experience there like that
show up isn't it crazy that you can't
show up is the same exact person to
every venue possible yo crumble Oh break
got that dude front man yeah front man
101 like dude like that's what I mean
yeah knowing what's appropriate like oh
my god dude to [__] one of the
biggest [__] lessons I learned in
high school I was goofing off one time
and my [__] math teacher pulled me
out in the hallway he was friends with
my dad so he can be a hard-ass on me and
he was like what the [__] are you doing
I was like I'm just [__] clown around
and he's like you want the difference
between a boy and a man is I was like I
don't know one's 18 he says no a man
knows the right place and right time for
everything blew my [__] mind took
that [__] with me till today that
shouldn't this water the difference
between a boy and a man as a man was the
right to have a right place for
everything and like front man yeah you
got it when you go up on stage you got
another right time right place like you
know I got to switch it up I got to be
more like tonight tonight I need to be
more personal people tonight tonight
where I can just [__] fall rock star
and give people the the [__] the show
experience you know like just knowing
the right time and right place to do all
that [__] or or like for a heckler to
try to spark spark you and you're like
am I gonna be a boy and respond back and
like have this like am I gonna be nice
or I'm gonna be a dick as yeah I'm
Portland we have services you gotta be a
dick see our hometown show cuz it's like
it's Portland that's our hometown like
oh good well yeah and if you heckle me
like dude yeah there's this [__] up
drunk guy just yelling [__] at me when
I'm trying to talk yelling shoot I don't
[__] know but I straight up I
straight up in the mic looked at him and
said hey I'm trying to [__] talk here
can you let me talk what do you do oh
and just [__] like stop talking I was
like and I think man I was just like
Jesus Christ man I was like I'm just
trying to
[__] talk let me talk to the people
yeah I said that and he was like and
then I just kept on doing my [__] yeah I
can't do that I mean sometimes you got
to pull people out of that though you
all do yeah it's like like I said like
dude that was our hometown crowd so it
was like the room was there for us we
were headlining like I could I could
have [__] called that guy a [__] and
like got him thrown out of the show and
people probably still would have loved
it
not really but you know like I remember
those crowds though it's like you know
it's really hard to be the bad guy
dude crowd dynamics are pretty it's
pretty weird like for comedians for
fitting that nowadays this like call-out
culture that's whatever I don't know
what the [__] I think the political
thing has made it okay to yell [__] at
the person on stage so I get people who
don't realize that and that's worse for
you well it is yeah this guy okay maybe
not no but this guy was just really
drunk right and that was it but minor
minor people who they they yell [__] as
like a reaction like just who they are
yeah and they don't realize that like
the speakers are facing you and I'm on
the other side of the speaker so I hear
you loud and clear [__] yeah so I I
have it's weird things so for me it's
not so like that it's not personal or
anything it's it's more of like they
don't like the song and some like
changes so change a song they yell that
or the or they'll uh or they'll uh I
don't know but people just say weird
stuff like yeah and it's like you're I'm
looking at you and I can hear you yeah
what do you expect to happen here yeah
so I I have had times where I've shut
down all the [__] music and I got on
the mic and I'm like hey man you're
yelling something here's a mic if you'd
like to say oh dude that's great I love
that don't they it's so it's happened in
in my hometown which I happen it was
like a night where I had like there was
easily 55 people there who knew me yeah
so people were like it's someone being
mean to Jamie I had my friends like
grabbing him and pulling them out and
then the security guards threw him out I
think it was like it wasn't even a big
deal but it was like but yeah people
people are [__] with our boy dude
yeah I mean so listen here's the thing
if you are a person who's listening in
first for whatever reason nobody has
ever taught you that it's not okay to
yell anything
any point if you're a person too crowded
this is at a movie at a rock show at I
mean unless the dude on stage says say
[__] yeah you say [__] exacts due to
your opinion like to me honestly evens
like when you're like telling a story
and and sentiment you like so as I grew
up in Portland and it sounds like [__]
yeah I think even that yeah you just
like interrupted not just the person
talking but everyone trying to listen
yeah I think you're ruin it for not just
the person on stage but everyone else in
the app yes so listen if you're on a
stage it's your turn to talk if you're
not on the stage shut up please yeah
exactly like Portland like where I can
confidently say which I don't say this a
lot like that's my [__] show that's
my stage that's my time that was my CD
really showing you in for the next uh do
we only play for like four times a year
but that's what I mean that's what makes
our shows pop we're very limited and
when I come to any guys today you
shouldn't be fun I'll [__] I'll list
you and [__] give you the the VIP
experience do you love it
dude I would love it to our logo have
you around man yeah because like yeah
because like I've seen like you do your
thing and I want to see you do are you
still DJ yeah I am I'm I'm I'm I'm still
keeping my Chronos alias like I'm yeah
I'm paying the bills like I still get
gigs like that like I just made a last
two nights like holiday parties and then
the local bar but I I play so sir I'm so
I don't even think about it I just I
don't know I don't you know without I
don't post it on social media yeah I
know yes like it's so I'm playing a
little bit of everything man it's like
it's like trying to make every single
person and they're happy which is the
most impossible thing I'm but but but
it's an effort and when it does pay off
just like for me when everyone the room
bounces I'm sure like when everyone in
the rooms [__] five and what's the
song or something I did it's the same
feeling better it's cool it's one
thought it makes all the shitty times
worth it but one thing for me that I
like doing is something a little battle
I like being able to so you're really
good at being from in an MC yeah it's
something that I'm you know I'm
increasing that I'm getting that skill
back but for honestly when it comes to
DJing I like to not touch
the mic and I like to just mix I like to
be the art I like to really get in I
want fun using my fingers when you have
both that's gonna be like I know well so
that's the thing is so so I'm still
playing my regular gigs like I'm playing
you know like the like EDM remixes and
just a top 40 hip-hop stuff but yeah
that's awesome we'll talk about it more
often spot yeah I don't want to put all
my eggs in one basket yeah everybody
hear about it but yeah I've been working
on a lot of my own stuff and I think you
know the next whatever progression I
want to push push some boundaries with
myself so excited yeah yeah well hey man
we've been getting up here quite a while
yeah dude
let's uh let's go ahead and wrap it up I
want to make sure that people know
everything they need to know about you
though where can they reach you where
can they hear ya so to find my band like
of course we're on all like major
platforms to listen to music on so you
know like Spotify Apple music all that
good [__] you can find us on all that
YouTube all that good [__] and then
we're all social medias it's at or /
dead crown band you can find a stare can
follow follow us we're pretty responsive
with people on our page and all that
[__] for me I'm just Kendall [__]
Jones yeah at dead Kendall I think it's
like my Twitter Instagram yeah if you
want [__] designed or videos made or
photos taken I probably helped you with
that you just hit me up for that [__]
and yeah I'm also I like people
sometimes don't get this but I work with
like all genres and all people so like I
just so happened like a lot of my
clientele is in the metal scene so it's
like but that's not where my skillset
lies I can literally do just about
[__] anything so yeah if you need
anything done how much boy and if I know
a lot of people that listen to this
they're probably like not like huge
metal kids but the one thing I will say
about dead crown because we do infuse
like a lot of hip-hop elements and [__]
especially on this new record the
biggest compliment that we got and what
really made us be like we need to steer
into this like rap [__] more is we would
go to shows we play and then we would
this started happening a lot to us we
would have a guy come up to us with like
his girlfriend and he'll be like yo dude
you guys were [__] sick
by the way this is my girlfriend she
[__] hates metal but she loves you
guys and you and like she had so much
fun at your guys's show I was like a
live show though I'm yeah you aren't a
fan of houses they can yes especially
metal or any rock yeah so we had a lot
of people coming up to us like at our
live shows being like yeah I don't even
like this [__] metal [__] and I love
you guys
like you guys are sick you guys like
having this vibe and this thing and this
energy and all that that's man yeah and
also a lot of people listen you know
Jake Hill is I am Jake Hill I don't
think he's a pretty big [__] rapper
right now oh yeah I don't know okay I'm
out of it there's someone probably
[__] listening this is this is how I
can tell you like how connected our
worlds really are at the other day
[__] are listening this know
who Jake Hill is okay I know they do
Jake Hill is actually on one of our
songs on honor on our new record okay
so which one is that what's called
coming up coming up coming up baby goes
and that's on our EP crucify me out now
via stasek records you can go listen to
it if you want but yeah it's a bunch of
metal [__] but we wrap and do all that
[__] too so yeah dude I've got I know a
lot of people that's the thing is being
a DJ I'm not just in one yeah I know you
know a lot just being who I am like dude
I was I've been an emo kid hardcore I've
been a butcher's also what I like about
you but everything like you're rooted
the same way that like all all of us
metal kids were rooted we all started I
was like emo seeing kids yep and that
like you just went this way we went that
way but at the core we all started out
in the same [__] yeah so it's like
that's why like I've never really had a
hard time like talking to you or
anything so it's like I know Jake comes
from the same place right like we're
like almost the same the same ground
same same person just different worlds
you you were thinking that I was like
you were like nervous to meet me or
something yeah same kind of people I
think you know when it when people let
their guards down and they and they let
down their their group their tribal
they're like who they think they are so
chill until someone gives you a reason
not to be chill Chrissa which is a
pretty big [__] reason you better
have a good excuse to Lou yeah show
because they're just dealing with some
[__] yeah so it's not worth it
just be chill people will be a better
place heck yes be [__] chill alright
be chill listeners speech he'll we've
got we've got Kendall John's man
listeners drink some [__] water to
ever yourself do a little yoga some DDP
yoga it's great a lot it like I know
it's pro wrestling [__] and like people
will be like oh this is [__] fake
outz wrestlers you looking through this
yeah but no it's actually like you'll do
that do that program and then you'll
look at your body and everything way
differently and you'll be like wow
mm-hmm and then if you want to explore
any sort of spirituality when it comes
to your body
yeah they recommend yoga yeah yoga's
great all around all right take care of
yourself listener junkie I love podcast
you